<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Protobear.dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Protobear.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Marnick De Grave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:05:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s the children who are wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/its-the-children-who-are-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:05:17 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/its-the-children-who-are-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stood at the front of the classroom, my laptop connected to a carefully crafted presentation on large language models, I felt a wave of pride. This class was my baby, six months of research, experiments, and talking to other experts distilled into a single class. I had practiced my class outside of school with friends both in person and online, they were filled with curiosity and engagement. But with my students? The enthusiasm wasn’t just missing, it felt like it had been sucked out of the room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I stood at the front of the classroom, my laptop connected to a carefully crafted presentation on large language models, I felt a wave of pride. This class was my baby, six months of research, experiments, and talking to other experts distilled into a single class. I had practiced my class outside of school with friends both in person and online, they were filled with curiosity and engagement. But with my students? The enthusiasm wasn’t just missing, it felt like it had been sucked out of the room.</p>
<p>Two students left the classroom early on, leaving their laptops behind. It wasn’t unusual, students sometimes step out for a phone call, a quick smoke (which I don&rsquo;t appreciate but, hey, they&rsquo;re adults), or a bathroom break. I figured they&rsquo;d be back in a few minutes.</p>
<p>They returned an hour and a half later, casually mentioning to a group of students (and to me, as I stood right there) that they had gone to smoke pot. Not just “stepped outside”, but openly admitted to choosing that over my class. I wasn’t angry, just… sad. Sad that my carefully designed lesson, something I hoped they would find interesting after hearing them talk about AI for months, was worth less to them than getting high.</p>
<p>I’m not really letting two students get to me, but the frequency of this kind of disengaged behavior is growing. Another moment that stands out was what I now call &ldquo;the Fortnite incident&rdquo;. It was the first time I got genuinely angry and raised my voice in class, and it surprised even me.</p>
<p>A student called me over during a lecture while still actively playing Fortnite. When I approached, he held up a finger and said, &ldquo;Wait a second&rdquo;. So that he could get to a safe spot in the game.</p>
<p>I couldn’t believe it. My frustration boiled over, and for the first time, I told a student to leave and come back next week. It felt disrespectful, not just to me, but to the entire class.</p>
<p>Then, about a month ago, there was the student who wasn’t even enrolled in my class. She approached me during a break to ask that I not call on her because she wasn’t actually taking the course. Naturally, I asked why she was there, to which she responded, &ldquo;out of interest.&rdquo; For a brief moment, I was happy and a bit flattered, and I said, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re interested in my class, why wouldn&rsquo;t I let you participate in it?&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Oh, I’m not interested in the material,&rdquo; she clarified. &ldquo;I’m interested in my friends.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Dear reader, I was too stunned to respond. I assumed she’d leave when class resumed, but she didn&rsquo;t. And at that point I just lacked the backbone to send her out.</p>
<p>These moments weren’t isolated incidents. From the start of the semester, I noticed a shift in behavior, a lack of engagement, a casual disregard for classroom etiquette, and an overall atmosphere that felt more like high school than higher education.</p>
<p>Halfway through the semester, I realized it wasn’t just the students who needed to change. I needed to change too. My lectures, no matter how carefully crafted, weren’t landing anymore. But with increasing class sizes growing too large for good practical instruction as I can&rsquo;t troubleshoot for 70 students, I felt stuck in a system that wasn’t working.</p>
<p>I won’t pretend I’ve handled this semester perfectly. My frustration with disengaged students started to bleed into how I treated the engaged ones. I lumped them all together, grew angry, and if I’m honest, wanted to win them over in a way. When I failed to get them actively engaged, it just made me feel even more sad. I’m learning to let that go.</p>
<p>Technology isn’t helping either. Large language models, ironically the subject of one of my last class, are also part of the problem. Students no longer ask me questions. Instead they ask AI. It’s faster, easier, and requires less effort than engaging with the material. But the shortcut comes at a cost: a shallow understanding that won’t hold up in the real world, or just straight-up wrong answers, and the time they spend chatting with the AI they are missing on instruction.</p>
<p>I know I can’t go back to the way things were. I need to rethink my approach by crafting in-class assignments that break up lectures and encourage collaboration. Assignments that can’t be outsourced to AI, forcing students to engage with each other and the material in ways only humans can. I&rsquo;ll let you know if I ever figure that one out as my lectures are all in the field of computer science.</p>
<p>I’m also talking to colleagues and students, trying to figure out what works and what doesn’t. Teaching in a changing world is a challenge, but it’s one I’m committed to facing.</p>
<p>Because at the end of the day, maybe the students aren’t entirely wrong. Maybe neither am I. But something needs to change.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Gave Away $232,772.2 in Free Advertising on r/MMORPG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-gave-away-232-772-2-in-free-advertising-on-r-mmorpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-gave-away-232-772-2-in-free-advertising-on-r-mmorpg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Story Behind r/MMORPG&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;r/MMORPG is a subreddit with its share of challenges, rough edges, and the occasional bad apple in both the community and the moderation team. However, what truly defines it is its dedicated community. These are people who love a very specific niche of gaming, coming to Reddit to discuss, discover, and share their passion, even to hate on games they dislike, which is a different kind of love, I suppose. This combination, though, makes the subreddit a bit of a minefield for developers. Even a whiff of positivity is sometimes dismissed as astroturfing, and many devs struggle to figure out how to engage without crossing invisible lines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Story Behind r/MMORPG</p>
<p>r/MMORPG is a subreddit with its share of challenges, rough edges, and the occasional bad apple in both the community and the moderation team. However, what truly defines it is its dedicated community. These are people who love a very specific niche of gaming, coming to Reddit to discuss, discover, and share their passion, even to hate on games they dislike, which is a different kind of love, I suppose. This combination, though, makes the subreddit a bit of a minefield for developers. Even a whiff of positivity is sometimes dismissed as astroturfing, and many devs struggle to figure out how to engage without crossing invisible lines.</p>
<p>Yet, it&rsquo;s hard to ignore the platform when r/MMORPG has over 50 million views annually and an average of 635k unique visitors per month, and it&rsquo;s still growing. For indie developers, this audience is too important to pass up as it is their core audience.</p>
<p>I joined the moderator team more than eight years ago, and six years ago, I became the subreddit’s owner. Well, &ldquo;administrator&rdquo; is a better term, after all, this is Reddit, not my private domain, and any value we create here ultimately belongs to the platform of which we see no return. Meanwhile Reddit is making deals selling user content to AI companies. But I’ve tried to make a positive impact where I can to improve the community for the people who enjoy it.</p>
<p>The Developer Spotlight program is one such initiative I introduced to bridge the gap between game developers and the r/MMORPG community. It allows developers to showcase their projects, gather valuable feedback, and engage with our passionate audience.</p>
<p>How the Spotlight Came to Be</p>
<p>Not many know this, but I used to work at an indie dev studio. Thankfully, I was an employee rather than one of the founders, but I still saw firsthand the struggles of promoting a game on a shoestring budget. It became clear that devs needed more opportunities to connect with audiences without paying an arm and a leg, and ideally, these opportunities would benefit everyone involved. To put things into perspective: GamesRadar charges about $5,000 for ads, estimating roughly 3,000 wishlists from the campaign. Meanwhile, OTK Media, the company representing streamers like Asmongold and Sodapoppin, charges $75,000 to showcase your game during their winter expo, and a 60-second ad during that same event costs $10,000. People deserve to be paid for their services, but for small developers, $75,000 could represent a year’s worth of income, something most simply can&rsquo;t justify spending.</p>
<p>That’s what the r/MMORPG Developer Spotlight was designed to do: offer a week of prime exposure where devs could introduce their projects to our community, share insights, and foster conversations, all without spending a cent. In return, we’d get great content for the subreddit, and our community would learn about upcoming games. It’s hard to beat free advertising, especially when it comes with a click-through rate of around 30%. Many of these spotlights have sparked articles, conversations, and lasting interest. By my own calculations we provide approximately $4,952.60 worth of free advertisement per spotlight. If you want to check my math, or check out what I estimate the value would be depending on a different CPM you can do so here.</p>
<p>We’ve had some standout examples over the years. Corepunk’s spotlight drew significant attention, as did Profane. One smaller project even managed to attract a bigger development team thanks to the exposure. It&rsquo;s moments like these that remind me why offering the platform for free has been a privilege, even if the community isn&rsquo;t always 100% supportive.</p>
<p>Challenges and Limitations</p>
<p>Of course, the spotlight isn’t without its flaws. The biggest limitation? Me. Organizing these spotlights takes time and energy, and I haven’t been able to delegate the workload effectively, as not many people are interested in working for free. Burnout is real, and sometimes I just can&rsquo;t find the time.</p>
<p>There’s also the challenge of making judgment calls, deciding which projects to feature and which to decline. Is a solo dev’s game a passion project or a thinly-veiled scam? I’ve denied games because I didn’t trust the developer, and I’ve tried to systematize the decision-making process, even going so far as to create a points system at one time. But in the end, it’s all subjective.</p>
<p>Then there’s Reddit itself. We don’t own the platform; we’re subject to its rules and limitations. I can’t set up a newsletter, add new functionality, tweak the CSS, or even send notifications, all things that could help us improve the spotlight program. Our reach and growth are ultimately limited by Reddit’s decisions.</p>
<p>To make things more complicated, Reddit’s mobile interface is taking over, which makes it even harder to highlight the content we want to feature. It’s something we’re still trying to work around.</p>
<p>The Future of the Spotlight, r/MMORPG, and My Place in It</p>
<p>I want to kick off another big round of developer spotlights, ideally with new developers, and collaborate more closely to create engaging content. As for the subreddit itself, it&rsquo;s doing well: we’ve grown significantly over the past year, with views increasing to 50.5 million and a steady rise in unique visitors and subscribers.</p>
<p>But as we move forward, I’ve been questioning my own place here. By 2026, I’ll have been involved with r/MMORPG for ten years, and I’m starting to think it might be time for me to step aside. There are others who could do an amazing job. And I’ll admit, I’m scared of letting go, scared of losing the industry contacts, scared of being just another player again. It’s something I’ve been mulling over for the past two years, and by the ten-year mark, I’ll have made my decision.</p>
<p>Closing Thoughts</p>
<p>What a roundabout way to announce I might be stepping down, all while just wanting to highlight the spotlight program and give a bit of context! But I’m genuinely proud of what we’ve built here. I’ve met incredible people along the way, and I hope I’ve made a difference, even if the community doesn’t always appreciate my efforts. I’m not looking for validation anymore; I just want to keep making things better, for however long I&rsquo;m still here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
