<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on Protobear.dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on Protobear.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Marnick De Grave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:05:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s the children who are wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/its-the-children-who-are-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:05:17 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/its-the-children-who-are-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stood at the front of the classroom, my laptop connected to a carefully crafted presentation on large language models, I felt a wave of pride. This class was my baby, six months of research, experiments, and talking to other experts distilled into a single class. I had practiced my class outside of school with friends both in person and online, they were filled with curiosity and engagement. But with my students? The enthusiasm wasn’t just missing, it felt like it had been sucked out of the room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I stood at the front of the classroom, my laptop connected to a carefully crafted presentation on large language models, I felt a wave of pride. This class was my baby, six months of research, experiments, and talking to other experts distilled into a single class. I had practiced my class outside of school with friends both in person and online, they were filled with curiosity and engagement. But with my students? The enthusiasm wasn’t just missing, it felt like it had been sucked out of the room.</p>
<p>Two students left the classroom early on, leaving their laptops behind. It wasn’t unusual, students sometimes step out for a phone call, a quick smoke (which I don&rsquo;t appreciate but, hey, they&rsquo;re adults), or a bathroom break. I figured they&rsquo;d be back in a few minutes.</p>
<p>They returned an hour and a half later, casually mentioning to a group of students (and to me, as I stood right there) that they had gone to smoke pot. Not just “stepped outside”, but openly admitted to choosing that over my class. I wasn’t angry, just… sad. Sad that my carefully designed lesson, something I hoped they would find interesting after hearing them talk about AI for months, was worth less to them than getting high.</p>
<p>I’m not really letting two students get to me, but the frequency of this kind of disengaged behavior is growing. Another moment that stands out was what I now call &ldquo;the Fortnite incident&rdquo;. It was the first time I got genuinely angry and raised my voice in class, and it surprised even me.</p>
<p>A student called me over during a lecture while still actively playing Fortnite. When I approached, he held up a finger and said, &ldquo;Wait a second&rdquo;. So that he could get to a safe spot in the game.</p>
<p>I couldn’t believe it. My frustration boiled over, and for the first time, I told a student to leave and come back next week. It felt disrespectful, not just to me, but to the entire class.</p>
<p>Then, about a month ago, there was the student who wasn’t even enrolled in my class. She approached me during a break to ask that I not call on her because she wasn’t actually taking the course. Naturally, I asked why she was there, to which she responded, &ldquo;out of interest.&rdquo; For a brief moment, I was happy and a bit flattered, and I said, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re interested in my class, why wouldn&rsquo;t I let you participate in it?&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Oh, I’m not interested in the material,&rdquo; she clarified. &ldquo;I’m interested in my friends.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Dear reader, I was too stunned to respond. I assumed she’d leave when class resumed, but she didn&rsquo;t. And at that point I just lacked the backbone to send her out.</p>
<p>These moments weren’t isolated incidents. From the start of the semester, I noticed a shift in behavior, a lack of engagement, a casual disregard for classroom etiquette, and an overall atmosphere that felt more like high school than higher education.</p>
<p>Halfway through the semester, I realized it wasn’t just the students who needed to change. I needed to change too. My lectures, no matter how carefully crafted, weren’t landing anymore. But with increasing class sizes growing too large for good practical instruction as I can&rsquo;t troubleshoot for 70 students, I felt stuck in a system that wasn’t working.</p>
<p>I won’t pretend I’ve handled this semester perfectly. My frustration with disengaged students started to bleed into how I treated the engaged ones. I lumped them all together, grew angry, and if I’m honest, wanted to win them over in a way. When I failed to get them actively engaged, it just made me feel even more sad. I’m learning to let that go.</p>
<p>Technology isn’t helping either. Large language models, ironically the subject of one of my last class, are also part of the problem. Students no longer ask me questions. Instead they ask AI. It’s faster, easier, and requires less effort than engaging with the material. But the shortcut comes at a cost: a shallow understanding that won’t hold up in the real world, or just straight-up wrong answers, and the time they spend chatting with the AI they are missing on instruction.</p>
<p>I know I can’t go back to the way things were. I need to rethink my approach by crafting in-class assignments that break up lectures and encourage collaboration. Assignments that can’t be outsourced to AI, forcing students to engage with each other and the material in ways only humans can. I&rsquo;ll let you know if I ever figure that one out as my lectures are all in the field of computer science.</p>
<p>I’m also talking to colleagues and students, trying to figure out what works and what doesn’t. Teaching in a changing world is a challenge, but it’s one I’m committed to facing.</p>
<p>Because at the end of the day, maybe the students aren’t entirely wrong. Maybe neither am I. But something needs to change.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to coffee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ode-to-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 10:31:31 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ode-to-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee, thou art my tempestuous companion, both invigorating and soothing. When my mornings are heavy with languor, you change my frame of mind. Your warmth runs through me, awakening my senses and shaking me from my comatose state, with your rich, redolent floral aroma and your lustrous dark color. It feels as though I could reach out and touch velvet itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is comfort in the ritual of your preparation, the whirring of the grinder, the bubbling brew, and the rising perfume that fills my small kitchen while the day&amp;rsquo;s first light catches on the steam that rises from the cup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, thou art my tempestuous companion, both invigorating and soothing. When my mornings are heavy with languor, you change my frame of mind. Your warmth runs through me, awakening my senses and shaking me from my comatose state, with your rich, redolent floral aroma and your lustrous dark color. It feels as though I could reach out and touch velvet itself.</p>
<p>There is comfort in the ritual of your preparation, the whirring of the grinder, the bubbling brew, and the rising perfume that fills my small kitchen while the day&rsquo;s first light catches on the steam that rises from the cup.</p>
<p>For a moment while waiting, as I stretch and yawn, feeling the world drift by, I see my deep, tangled thoughts unravel. For just a moment, the world outside the kitchen ceases to exist, and there is only you and I.</p>
<p>You are both the comforting embrace that cradles me and the spark that ignites me; a codependent yet undeniably beautiful bond. Here&rsquo;s to you, coffee, the magic that brings the mundane to life, one glorious cup at a time.</p>
<p>So, to whom it may concern: Get the coffee machine fixed, or I will start invoicing my daily trips to Madmum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve got a friend (that wants to take your money) in me.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/youve-got-a-friend-that-wants-to-take-your-money-in-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:12:39 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/youve-got-a-friend-that-wants-to-take-your-money-in-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear tech bro’s,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can we just stop with this late-stage capitalist nonsense of creating inferior products to replace things we already have? It’s like a strategy to erode our reliance on actual skills and tools, all to charge us a monthly fee for something we can already do with minimal effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, a tech company has launched a product aimed at replacing the idea of friends as a support system. It introduces a constant, chatty presence in your life, making sure you never have a moment of peace. Because god forbid you form an actual thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear tech bro’s,</p>
<p>Can we just stop with this late-stage capitalist nonsense of creating inferior products to replace things we already have? It’s like a strategy to erode our reliance on actual skills and tools, all to charge us a monthly fee for something we can already do with minimal effort.</p>
<p>This week, a tech company has launched a product aimed at replacing the idea of friends as a support system. It introduces a constant, chatty presence in your life, making sure you never have a moment of peace. Because god forbid you form an actual thought.</p>
<p>Before we dive deeper, let’s watch the product video together:</p>
<p>What the actual fuck did we just witness?</p>
<p>This device features an always-on microphone(I assume, the video shows it both ways) that texts you comments on your actions, responds to nonsensical remarks, makes judgments, and interrupts your activities—basically, it pretends to be an important figure in your life while actually being invasive and annoying.</p>
<p>We often throw around Orwell’s name whenever something feels dystopian, but in this case, it seems apt. Orwell would probably be alarmed by such a device—a “friend” that monitors your every move, potentially manipulates your perceptions of reality as it is happening, and records your interactions. It’s like a creepy version of Big Brother masquerading as a&hellip; well&hellip; friend.</p>
<p>The concept video is clearly overblown marketing for what is essentially just a wrapper around chatgpt. The claim that it’s been in development for years is laughable - The product is so underbaked and obviously in the concept stage. How can the AI make a comment on a show you’re watching if you had to press a button to talk to it afterwards? Is it recording your screen? Audio analysis? How does the AI have opinions on a show? Is this curated by other people? Does the AI know your preferences and says things to align with how you think? That comment the guy got about losing the game. Yeah trash talk is funny, but imagine getting that message when your confidence is low.</p>
<p>It’s, well, a friend — an AI friend that can go with you anywhere, experience things with you, and just be there with you all the time. “It’s very supportive, very validating, it’ll encourage your ideas,” Schiffmann Interview with “The Verge”</p>
<p>A friend? No. It’s not. People get lonely. I’ve been there myself. But having an AI around your neck that says “You go girl, eat that cheeseburger!” isn’t solving loneliness. It’s making it worse by teaching people to expect from humans what they get from an AI in terms of communication and what support looks like, thereby unlearning real coping mechanisms.</p>
<p>I suspect all the processing happens in a mobile app, and the necklace is just a Bluetooth microphone. At least if that’s true, you might be able to repurpose the device when the company inevitably goes under.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, billions will be sunk into gadgets like this, which will eventually end up in landfills. All this while we bemoan the planet’s burning state, with AI set to use more energy by 2026 than Japan, a country of 125 million people. All thanks to unchecked corporate greed.</p>
<p>In 1979 IBM said in a presentation</p>
<p>“A computer can never be held accountable, therefore a computer must never make a management decision” -</p>
<p>So to end this rant I’d like to steal that quote and make it my own.</p>
<p>“A computer isn’t a fucking person, and therefore can’t be your fucking friend.”</p>
<p>Disclaimer: This article was originally published on my GitHub Pages blog. Minor edits may have been made for clarity and formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
