<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Protobear.dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Protobear.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Marnick De Grave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 12:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strange Weather in Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/strange-weather-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:37:40 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/strange-weather-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rarely write about books because I only read about 10 a year, and I don’t feel confident in my taste or vocabulary. But I want to talk about Strange Weather in Tokyo. I’ve picked it up and put it down several times before finally finishing it, and it’s beautifully written: poetic, intimate, and full of understated internal struggles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re into short, wholesome romance novels, go read it before continuing. It’s a quick read – my Kobo says it took me 4.5 hours. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I rarely write about books because I only read about 10 a year, and I don’t feel confident in my taste or vocabulary. But I want to talk about Strange Weather in Tokyo. I’ve picked it up and put it down several times before finally finishing it, and it’s beautifully written: poetic, intimate, and full of understated internal struggles.</p>
<p>If you’re into short, wholesome romance novels, go read it before continuing. It’s a quick read – my Kobo says it took me 4.5 hours. </p>
<p>Spoilers ahead.</p>
<p>Strange Weather in Tokyo unfolds as a series of vignettes, following the evolving relationship between two characters: Tsukiko Omachi, a woman in her thirties, and Harutsuna Matsumoto, her former high school teacher, known as &ldquo;Sensei.&rdquo; His age isn&rsquo;t specified, but he is likely in his seventies. They reconnect by chance at an izakaya, a Japanese bar, transitioning from drinking companions to friends and ultimately to partners.</p>
<p>The story&rsquo;s structure feels carefully chosen, showing chronological moments that gently reveal the growth of their bond. It focuses less on grand events and more on the quiet, intimate ways people connect, with much of the understated drama unfolding within Tsukiko’s inner world.</p>
<p>A review by Ashley Hajimirsadeghi critiqued the novel, stating, “I cannot get past the fact the plot is about the high school teacher and the girl. Maybe because I’m used to looking at gender issues from a critical lens, I find the teacher’s behavior to be problematic.”  While I respect her perspective and I think it’s important to share that perspective, I see the story differently, perhaps because I haven’t personally experienced predatory behavior, which could shape how I interpret the characters.</p>
<p>What some might find uncomfortable, I see as intentional. The story isn’t just about a romance; it’s about two lonely, adrift people finding meaning through each other. Sensei’s &ldquo;teacherly&rdquo; demeanor reflects both his personality and his role in Tsukiko’s life. He teaches her to savor life’s simple pleasures and embrace moments without expectations, while Tsukiko reminds him there’s still more life to live. They don’t fix each other, but they complement one another. It’s a relationship built on mutual growth, not perfection, and that makes it feel deeply human.</p>
<p>The ending felt perfect, offering only a brief glimpse of the relationship itself through a short chapter that captures its aftermath. Initially, it gave me a moment of whiplash – shifting from a calm joy to a tear slipping down my cheek as I read on the train. The inclusion of Parade, a companion short story, softened the sadness for me and reinforced some of the novel’s central themes.</p>
<p>It’s a slow, tender read, full of evocative descriptions that make you feel like you’re right there with them at the bar. If sake weren’t so disgusting, I’d imagine myself drinking along with them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Letter for a New Year’s Dawn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/a-simple-letter-for-a-new-years-dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 08:00:23 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/a-simple-letter-for-a-new-years-dawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Belgium, and especially in Flanders, there’s a tradition called the “nieuwjaarsbrief” or New Year’s letter. On the first of January, children present these letters to their parents, godparents, and sometimes other family members, often reading them aloud at family gatherings. It’s a moment of warmth and gratitude, and for the children it&amp;rsquo;s a moment of pushing through the anxiety of demonstrating their poor reading skills in order to receive their gift or envelope of cash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Belgium, and especially in Flanders, there’s a tradition called the “nieuwjaarsbrief” or New Year’s letter. On the first of January, children present these letters to their parents, godparents, and sometimes other family members, often reading them aloud at family gatherings. It’s a moment of warmth and gratitude, and for the children it&rsquo;s a moment of pushing through the anxiety of demonstrating their poor reading skills in order to receive their gift or envelope of cash.</p>
<p>Once you enter secondary education, you usually stop writing these letters. However, godparents typically continue to show their care by giving you gifts. Now, with both of my godparents passing away in the past eighteen months, I’m stepping into a new year without their presence.</p>
<p>Because they teased me for years about whether I was ready to read my letter, even as an adult, I’ve decided to write another one. Once more allowing myself to express my hopes, dreams, and wishes for this coming year, just as I did long ago. It’s a way to honor their memory and what they meant to me.</p>
<p>Dearest friends and kindred hearts,
A brand new year in silence starts.
Let hopes and dreams now rise and sing,
Like gentle birds who greet the spring.</p>
<p>May laughter bloom in common ground,
And gentle peace at last be found.
Where strife and fear once held their reign,
May healing light now ease our pain.</p>
<p>From crowded halls to quiet lands,
Let kindness guide our gentle hands.
With wars and worries cast aside,
May truth and mercy be our guide.</p>
<p>No cherished dream shall slip away,
As dawn reveals a brighter day.
With courage true and an open heart,
We’ll mend this world in every part.</p>
<p>Your hopeful voice when skies aren&rsquo;t clear,</p>
<p>Marnick De Grave
1 January, 2025</p>
<p>Alternatively, you can always opt for the easy way out, as I did as an adult, and whenever they teased me, I would simply respond with:</p>
<p>Dearest godmother and father,
A gift is fine, but cash goes farther.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Games That Stole My Heart, Broke It, or Just Wore Me Out in 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/best-games-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/best-games-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024 was a strange year for me when it came to gaming. It wasn’t a bad year by any means, there were plenty of great games. But nothing truly stood out as my game. Usually, I gravitate toward story-heavy, deeply immersive experiences, but this year I found myself leaning into fun, quick entertainment instead. Maybe it was the state of the world, or maybe I just needed games that didn’t ask too much of me. Not to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t play some RPGs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2024 was a strange year for me when it came to gaming. It wasn’t a bad year by any means, there were plenty of great games. But nothing truly stood out as my game. Usually, I gravitate toward story-heavy, deeply immersive experiences, but this year I found myself leaning into fun, quick entertainment instead. Maybe it was the state of the world, or maybe I just needed games that didn’t ask too much of me. Not to say I didn&rsquo;t play some RPGs.</p>
<p>There was a lot of joy to be found in genres I don’t usually pay much attention to, and I tried a lot of new things (maybe not as much as I wanted to). But not everything landed. Some games failed to hook me, or worse, frustrated me with baffling design choices or poor communication.</p>
<p>Still, the games on this list are a reflection of my 2024: messy, unexpected, and occasionally brilliant. Whether they stole my heart, let me down, or were just… fine, here’s everything that stuck with me this year.</p>
<p>The games I liked</p>
<p>These games aren&rsquo;t perfect. But I liked them nonetheless</p>
<p>The games on this list aren’t ranked in any particular order.</p>
<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</p>
<p>Was it the best RPG of all time? No.
But was it fun? Did I enjoy exploring the maps, the gameplay, and the fact that it respected my time? Absolutely.</p>
<p>I think it’s okay to enjoy flawed games, especially when they’re trying something new. Sure, I have plenty of critiques. The world often felt like a stage, with no real life outside of what it wanted me to focus on. A lot of little things bothered me, too. And yet, I kept playing and genuinely looked forward to every session.</p>
<p>That said, controller support on PC (at least with my 8BitDo Pro) was a frustrating experience, especially when it came to selecting spells. It’s a shame, because the rest of the game deserved better in that department.</p>
<p>Helldivers 2</p>
<p>Pretending to be an unwitting cog in the military-industrial complex, delivered with satire so thick you’d think it impossible to miss, with friends has never been more fun.</p>
<p>Helldivers 2 was great for what it was: a game that brought me together with friends for a few weeks of chaos and laughs before we all collectively moved on. And that’s okay. The game didn’t fail; it did exactly what it set out to do. It captured our attention while it lasted and still has a dedicated player base keeping it alive.</p>
<p>More games like this, please.</p>
<p>Astro Bot</p>
<p>If you’re going to steal, do it well, and Sony clearly said “We want Mario”. And Mario they got. Astro Bot doesn’t need a story because it’s just plain fun from start to finish.</p>
<p>Does it deserve Game of the Year accolades? Honestly, I’m not sure, it’s a tough call. The game executes everything it sets out to do exceptionally well. It offers a variety of playstyles and constantly introduces fresh ideas, keeping the gameplay from ever feeling stale. I loved my time with it.</p>
<p>But at the same time, it feels like an advertisement, a showcase for Sony’s tech and characters. So, while it’s great, it also leaves me feeling a little conflicted.</p>
<p>The Bazaar</p>
<p>The gameplay is solid, the art is charming, and it’s just plain fun. Perfect for when you’ve got a few spare minutes but can’t commit to babysitting live matches. If you’re familiar with “auto chess” or the autobattler genre, this will feel instantly recognizable.</p>
<p>Your only actions happen between rounds as you build out your setup. Once a round starts, it’s completely out of your hands. This makes it great for quick bursts of play as you can dive in for 5 minutes, forget it’s running for another 25, and then pick up right where you left off.</p>
<p>Metaphor: ReFantazio</p>
<p>It’s Persona, but also not. If you’re a fan of Persona, give it a shot but keep in mind its different in some aspects. If you’re not a fan, still give it a shot. I especially enjoyed playing it in short bursts, which makes it a great fit for the Steam Deck. That said, developers, please stop making games where you can’t save anywhere and anywhere, it’s 2024, let us live our lives!</p>
<p>For a game called Metaphor, it doesn’t shy away from laying its themes on thick. But after playing Helldivers 2, I’m more convinced than ever that media literacy is dead, and sometimes you really do need to spoonfeed concepts to people.</p>
<p>And if you’re someone who doesn’t like politics in your games, well… sorry, but it’s time to grow up. Nearly every story reveals the writer’s biases and has some level of political undercurrent. That said, this might not be the game for you.</p>
<p>For me, it was the perfect story to end 2024 on.</p>
<p>Animal Well</p>
<p>Well, fuck me. After claiming all games are political, here comes Animal Well, a game that doesn’t even have dialogue. It’s all about observing the environment, uncovering hidden bits and pieces, and letting the world tell its story without saying a word. Which means its up to your interpretation.</p>
<p>It’s hard, intricate, and undeniably beautiful. If you’re into metroidvanias, go give it a shot.</p>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</p>
<p>I haven’t spent enough time with this one to call it “amazing” or “GOTY-worthy,” but from what I’ve played, it’s absolutely beautiful and feels authentic to the Indiana Jones vibe. It’s good, it’s entertaining, but it also feels a bit like a movie turned into a game, which isn’t necessarily a bad thing depending on what you want from that moment..</p>
<p>What I really appreciate is how the game trusts you. It doesn’t hold your hand, encourages you to backtrack, find new items, and unlock different paths. It’s a refreshing approach, and I’m excited to give it another go when it releases on PS5.</p>
<p>I played it on Game Pass (a service I’m not overly fond of) and while it ran well on my PC, this is the kind of game I’d rather enjoy from the comfort of my sofa.</p>
<p>Chants of Sennaar</p>
<p>Though it released in 2023, I only got around to playing it this year. It’s a puzzle game where you decipher languages to understand the people and figure out your objectives as you climb a tower.</p>
<p>What really stands out is how the game explores the relationship between language and culture. It’s a fascinating game wrapped in an engaging and beautifully designed experience. Definitely worth checking out if you enjoy puzzles and thoughtful world-building.</p>
<p>Jeff: The Game (Marvel Rivals)</p>
<p>Not in a million years would I have predicted this game would succeed, let alone that I’d actually like it. Netease doesn’t exactly inspire confidence when it comes to avoiding nickel-and-diming tactics or straight up abandoning the game down the line. And honestly, the game’s future isn’t guaranteed. It’s riding the hype cycle right now, but I’ve had friends come out of the woodwork to play this with me, friends I haven’t heard from in years.</p>
<p>And that? That makes me happy. What makes me sad, though, is how it reminds me of what Overwatch could’ve been. I’ll always prefer first-person shooters, and Overwatch still has better gamefeel and, in my opinion, superior map design. It unfortunately comes nowhere close to the fun that I have with Rivals, and it&rsquo;s all because of that stupid shark. That goddamn adorable shark, Jeff, has completely stolen my heart. I’ve never really been into Marvel comics outside of X-Men, but here I am, diving into them because of that delightful little apex predator.</p>
<p>Take my money, Jeff. You’ve earned it.</p>
<p>Games that don&rsquo;t really think of as games?</p>
<p>Some of the things I played this year feel less like “games” and more like “toys.” They’re not so much about playing as they are about fiddling and experimenting. But does that distinction even matter?</p>
<p>SUMMERHOUSE</p>
<p>It’s hard to put this game into words, so I’ll borrow the developers’ description: “A tiny building game about beautiful lived-in houses. No rules or restrictions, just pure creativity.”</p>
<p>And honestly, that sums it up perfectly. I enjoyed it immensely. Sometimes, the right game finds you at exactly the right time.</p>
<p>Spirit City: Lofi Sessions</p>
<p>If I think SUMMERHOUSE barely qualifies as a game, then Spirit City: Lofi Sessions is even further from it. It’s practically a productivity tool. With trackers, lists, and a built-in Pomodoro timer, it’s designed to help you get things done rather than just play.</p>
<p>That said, I wish there were a mobile version so those lists didn’t live exclusively on my PC. At the very least, a Mac version would be nice.</p>
<p>But if you enjoy listening to lofi hip-hop while working, decorating rooms and characters, and generally love cozy vibes, it’s worth a try. It’s oddly satisfying and makes productivity feel a little less like a chore.</p>
<p>Tiny Glade</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m breaking my own rule her of including only one image per game, it&rsquo;s just that gorgeous. It’s similar in concept to SUMMERHOUSE, a game about creativity and building. But with a completely different art style and far more detail. It’s proof that if you give people a canvas, they’ll create art (and apparently half the locations from Lord of the Rings).</p>
<p>Once more I&rsquo;m going to give you the developers&rsquo; description because it does a great job at explaining what it is: &ldquo;Tiny Glade is a small diorama builder where you doodle whimsical castles, cozy cottages &amp; romantic ruins. Explore gridless building chemistry as the game adorns your glades with procedural detail. No management, combat or goals: just kick back and turn forgotten meadows into lovable dioramas.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Just go take a look at some screenshots here.</p>
<p>The Games I Disliked</p>
<p>I’m not saying these are bad games. For one reason or another, though, I played them and just didn’t enjoy myself. Maybe they didn’t click with me, or maybe I expected more from them than they delivered.</p>
<p>Dragon&rsquo;s Dogma 2</p>
<p>I tried it a few times, and I was really excited to play it based on what I heard others say but it wasn&rsquo;t a good experience on PC for me. The controls weren&rsquo;t doing it for me and the world failed to grab me fast enough. I can&rsquo;t really describe it any other way as tedious for me.</p>
<p>Corepunk</p>
<p>I’ve already written about my experience with Corepunk, and you can read more about it here.</p>
<p>I still hold out hope they can course correct, maybe a Steam launch can save them from their rocky start. But the real reason it’s on this list is their absolutely piss poor communication. Their servers were down for an entire week, and not a single update was posted on their site. And I don&rsquo;t want to keep opening the launcher to see updates either.</p>
<p>Everything about this game feels like a frustrating experience. Why is the launcher a portable file and not a proper installer? Most people aren’t going to bother with extracting a folder, they’ll take one look at it and move on because DLL files scary. It’s such a baffling choice for accessibility which might as well be the subtitle for this game. Corepunk: Making baffling accessibility choices.</p>
<p>The Plucky Squire</p>
<p>Again, this isn’t a bad game, it’s just not for me. Everything felt too simplistic, which might be because I’m not the target audience, and it dragged on a bit too much for my taste. They’ve introduced a new mode that promises to speed up the pace, so I might give it another shot. Still, I can’t help but feel they could’ve done more with their unique concept and no amount of pace fixing will make the puzzles harder.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set a custom domain name as a handle on Bluesky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/how-to-set-a-custom-domain-name-as-a-handle-on-bluesky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:25:08 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/how-to-set-a-custom-domain-name-as-a-handle-on-bluesky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some people think that setting a custom domain as your Bluesky handle requires self-hosting or managing complex systems, but that’s not the case. Unlike platforms like Mastodon, which can involve hosting an entire server, Bluesky’s identity verification system is much simpler. You don’t need to run a server or host anything, just prove that you own the domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s a straightforward and secure process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your domain isn’t tied to a single username, either. You can even use subdomains or create handles that overlap with existing domains. For example, my Bluesky handle is @protobear.dev, which matches my domain, protobear.dev. But I’m not limited to that. I could create a separate account just for my blog and set the handle to @blog.protobear.dev if I wanted. Just note that domain-based handles don’t work like email addresses, you can’t use &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:blog@protobear.dev&#34;&gt;blog@protobear.dev&lt;/a&gt; as a handle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some people think that setting a custom domain as your Bluesky handle requires self-hosting or managing complex systems, but that’s not the case. Unlike platforms like Mastodon, which can involve hosting an entire server, Bluesky’s identity verification system is much simpler. You don’t need to run a server or host anything, just prove that you own the domain.</p>
<p>It’s a straightforward and secure process.</p>
<p>Your domain isn’t tied to a single username, either. You can even use subdomains or create handles that overlap with existing domains. For example, my Bluesky handle is @protobear.dev, which matches my domain, protobear.dev. But I’m not limited to that. I could create a separate account just for my blog and set the handle to @blog.protobear.dev if I wanted. Just note that domain-based handles don’t work like email addresses, you can’t use <a href="mailto:blog@protobear.dev">blog@protobear.dev</a> as a handle.</p>
<p>Here’s how simple it is to set this up:</p>
<ol>
<li>Generate a key from Bluesky.</li>
<li>Add a DNS record.</li>
<li>Click refresh.</li>
</ol>
<p>That’s it! You’re done! It’s genuinely that simple.</p>
<p>To make this less intimidating, I’ll walk you through the process step by step using a domain I already own for a project I’m working on. Even if it seems daunting at first, you’ll see there’s really not much to it.</p>
<p>Important: While it&rsquo;s not technically difficult to change your handle it involves many different technologies you might not be familiar with, and understandably have questions about as its not entirely unlikely your livelihood is coupled to the domain you&rsquo;d wish to use. That&rsquo;s why at the bottom there&rsquo;s some extra explanations about these technologies, or questions you might have.</p>
<p>Instructions</p>
<p>Before we begin, you’ll need to have a Bluesky account already set up. If you don’t have one yet, create an account and log in. Once you&rsquo;re ready, head over to the Settings page to get started.</p>
<p>Generating the DNS Record</p>
<p>On the Settings page, navigate to the Account section.</p>
<p>On the Account page, click on Handle to start the process of setting your custom domain as your handle.</p>
<p>Click on I have my own domain.</p>
<p>Once you&rsquo;ve clicked I have my own domain, enter your desired domain name into the field at the top. This will generate the DNS information you need to add to your domain&rsquo;s settings. Make note of the Host, Type, and Value fields, as you&rsquo;ll need these to update your DNS records.</p>
<p>Adding the DNS Record to your Registrar</p>
<p>Go to your domain registrar&rsquo;s website (if you don’t already have a domain, I recommend Cloudflare) and navigate to the section where you can manage DNS Records.</p>
<p>A DNS record is essentially a file associated with your domain name that tells the DNS system where to direct traffic. Don’t worry, we’re not touching the essential records like A, AAAA, or CNAME records that control your website’s functionality.</p>
<p>Instead, we’re adding a TXT record, which is a simple text-based record often used to verify ownership of a domain. Adding this record poses no security risk to your domain, and Bluesky can’t take control of it.</p>
<p>Once you’re in the DNS Records section, look for an option to Add a Record—this is where we’ll add the TXT record for Bluesky.</p>
<p>Other Registrars</p>
<p>To make this process even easier, I’ve included links to the documentation for adding DNS records for several popular domain registrars. These guides will walk you through the exact steps for your registrar:</p>
<ul>
<li>GoDaddy</li>
<li>Namecheap</li>
<li>Porkbun</li>
<li>Hostinger</li>
<li>Cloudflare</li>
<li>Wordpress</li>
</ul>
<p>Adding the DNS Record</p>
<p>When you click on Add record you&rsquo;ll get something like this.</p>
<p>The first thing you should do is change the type to TXT.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re using Cloudflare, don’t worry if the interface looks a bit different initially. When you change the type to TXT, the UI will update to match the format for TXT records. After making this change, it should look something like this:</p>
<p>From here, you can input the required details provided by Bluesky. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Name: This will typically be _atproto (or whatever Bluesky specifies).</li>
<li>Content: Copy and paste the unique value generated by Bluesky for verification.</li>
<li>TTL: Leave it as the default. (Auto)</li>
</ul>
<p>You can find these details on the change handle modal on the Bluesky settings page.</p>
<p>The Name field should match what Bluesky refers to as the Host, and the Content field should be filled in with the Value provided by Bluesky.</p>
<p>Once you’ve entered these details, save the record. This step links your Bluesky handle to your domain and verifies your ownership.</p>
<p>You should now see your new TXT record listed alongside your other DNS records, similar to the image above.</p>
<p>Depending on your domain registrar, it may take some time for the changes to propagate. With Cloudflare, this process usually takes about a minute.</p>
<p>Once you&rsquo;ve waited for about a minute, go back to Bluesky and click Verify DNS Record to complete the process.</p>
<p>If the record has been added correctly, you’ll see a green checkmark, and the button will change to say &ldquo;Update to {domain name}&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Click this button, and your Bluesky handle will be updated to the domain name you set up. Congratulations! You’re now using your custom domain as your Bluesky handle!</p>
<p>If Bluesky doesn’t find the DNS record right away, don’t panic! Sometimes it takes a little while for changes to propagate. Depending on factors outside of your control (Like the DNS network) and the registrar you chose (which is within your control), propagation can take up to 72 hours in rare cases.</p>
<p>To speed things up, make sure the TTL (Time-To-Live) value for your record is set to Auto or a low value like 15 minutes. This will ensure the changes update more quickly. Once the domain is successfully verified, you can change the TTL back to a longer value to reduce unnecessary DNS traffic.</p>
<p>Patience is key, just wait a bit and try verifying again!</p>
<p>Optional: Adding subdomains as handles</p>
<p>You can also use this setup for team members by creating subdomains for each individual. For example, if your main domain is example.com, you could assign subdomains like alice.example.com or bob.example.com to specific team members.</p>
<p>Simply follow the same steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Add a TXT record for each subdomain in your DNS settings.</li>
<li>Use the Host field to specify the subdomain (e.g., _atproto.alice for alice.example.com).</li>
<li>Fill in the Value provided by Bluesky for each account.</li>
</ol>
<p>This allows each team member to have a unique handle tied to your organization’s domain, making it both professional and secure!</p>
<p>QYDA: Questions You Didn&rsquo;t Ask</p>
<p>What’s a registrar?</p>
<p>A registrar is the service you use to register and manage a domain name. Think of it as the storefront where you purchase the rights to use a specific domain (e.g., example.com). Registrars also provide tools to manage your domain, like setting up DNS records or renewing your ownership. Popular registrars include Cloudflare, GoDaddy, and Namecheap.</p>
<p>What’s DNS?</p>
<p>The Domain Name System (DNS) is like the internet’s address book. When you type a domain name (e.g., example.com) into your browser, DNS translates it into the numerical IP address of the server hosting that website. Without DNS, you’d need to memorize long strings of numbers to visit websites instead of using easy-to-remember names.</p>
<p>DNS also helps direct other internet traffic, like email or authentication services, by linking domain names to specific servers or systems.</p>
<p>What’s a DNS record?</p>
<p>A DNS record is a set of instructions in the DNS that tells internet systems what to do with your domain name. It’s essentially a piece of data that answers questions like:</p>
<ul>
<li>“Where is this website hosted?” (via an A or AAAA record pointing to an IP address)</li>
<li>“Which server should handle mail for this domain?” (via an MX record).</li>
</ul>
<p>DNS records also serve other purposes, such as verification. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>SPF or DKIM records: Confirm email authenticity.</li>
<li>TXT records: Provide additional information about your domain.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the case of Bluesky, a TXT record is used to verify that your Bluesky account belongs to the owner of a specific domain. This allows you to connect your domain name as your handle securely.</p>
<p>What’s a PDS?</p>
<p>A Personal Data Server (PDS) is a system that stores and manages your online identity and content on decentralized networks like Bluesky’s AT Protocol. Instead of relying entirely on centralized platforms like traditional social networks, a PDS gives you control over your data, allowing you to move between platforms or even self-host if you want.</p>
<p>Think of a PDS as your personal hub on the web. It ensures that you own your content and identity, and not the platform you’re using.</p>
<p>Does this mean I’m self-hosting now?</p>
<p>No, setting up a custom domain for your Bluesky handle doesn’t mean you’re self-hosting. You’re not hosting a server or managing any of the technical backend systems. All you’re doing is proving ownership of a domain by adding a DNS record, which Bluesky uses to verify and associate your domain name with your handle.</p>
<p>In simpler terms, you’re just adding a tag to your domain to show that “you own this,” and Bluesky does the rest. It’s a lightweight process that doesn’t require any ongoing maintenance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I didn&#39;t like Corepunk that much.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/i-didnt-like-corepunk-that-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:02:47 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/i-didnt-like-corepunk-that-much/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the summer, I finally purchased Corepunk, a game I had eagerly anticipated for years. Its top-down viewpoint, MOBA-inspired combat, and mixed progression systems promised a refreshing departure from the usual MMORPG formula. The aesthetic was striking, and the idea of a world that wouldn’t hold my hand through exploration intrigued me. After hosting an AMA for the game, the team even sent me a PR package, complete with my now-favorite socks and pen, which only added to my excitement. But as the saying goes, “The higher the climb, the harder the fall.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the summer, I finally purchased Corepunk, a game I had eagerly anticipated for years. Its top-down viewpoint, MOBA-inspired combat, and mixed progression systems promised a refreshing departure from the usual MMORPG formula. The aesthetic was striking, and the idea of a world that wouldn’t hold my hand through exploration intrigued me. After hosting an AMA for the game, the team even sent me a PR package, complete with my now-favorite socks and pen, which only added to my excitement. But as the saying goes, “The higher the climb, the harder the fall.”</p>
<p>When I first attempted to play Corepunk in the summer, I encountered a bug that prevented me from accepting the opening quest. Frustrating, but I chalked it up to the beta phase and resolved to try again after its soft launch in November. Unfortunately, my excitement soon turned into disappointment. After just 60 or so minutes of gameplay, I found myself logging out, disillusioned and frustrated.</p>
<p>Some of my frustrations are fixable, while others stem from what I see as core design flaws. My initial excitement about the game’s hands-off approach to navigation quickly morphed into my biggest annoyance: Corepunk doesn’t just fail to guide players; it actively undermines exploration with its lack of support.</p>
<p>I’ve broken down my core issues (pun intended) into three punkts (You see, the joke here is that punkt in German means point, I know, jokes are better when explained): Navigation, Questing, and Combat.</p>
<p>Navigation</p>
<p>One of the things I initially appreciated was the absence of big, flashing markers showing me where to go. I thought, “Finally, a game that trusts players to explore!” But Corepunk doesn’t complement this design choice with the tools needed to make exploration rewarding. Here are some key issues:</p>
<p>No Navigation Signs</p>
<p>There are no clear indicators of where to go. Buildings may have signs, but many require you to hover over symbols to understand what they represent. This breaks immersion and slows progress. I&rsquo;m not asking for big arrows leading me to my destination, but maybe a road sign or two. Or the ability to ask a guard?</p>
<p>Perspective Challenges</p>
<p>The top-down view, while aesthetically pleasing, makes it nearly impossible to rely on landmarks for navigation. You can’t look into the distance, and while this limitation is intentional, the terrain isn’t unique enough to compensate. Games like Diablo and Path of Exile work around this by designing corridors that naturally guide the player. Diablo 4 even incorporates vistas to provide a sense of direction. Corepunk, by contrast, leaves players adrift.</p>
<p>Unclear Quest Objectives</p>
<p>For one quest, I had to locate an NPC in a specific building. I remembered seeing the building before, complete with its sign, so I confidently went there. But when I tried to enter through the door next to the neon sign, it was locked and mentioned lacking a key. After wasting time trying to “solve” this puzzle, I discovered there was no puzzle and the NPC was actually in a nearby courtyard. With no visual indicators to identify them like, god, I don&rsquo;t know, how about their name above their head? To make matters worse, players crowded the NPC, and their wandering made it even harder to find them. The quest text didn’t clarify any of this, leaving me frustrated. ESO actually does this really well, if you were to turn off the UI and purely rely on quest text it does a really good job explaining you where you need to go.</p>
<p>This lack of clarity is more than frustrating: it’s exhausting. Fixing this would likely require a significant rework of the world design. For future zones, developers could add clearer visual cues and improved quest text to help players but I fear for the already in-game zones its too late.</p>
<p>Questing</p>
<p>Corepunk’s quest design only exacerbates its navigation problems. Here are three quests that highlight the issues and made me question my sanity:</p>
<ol>
<li>The First Optional Quest</li>
</ol>
<p>Early on, I spoke to an NPC (who had no name above their head or other indicators to suggest they offered a quest) who tasked me with searching barrels for mana crystals “on the farms.” With no map indicators or clear textual guidance, I spent several minutes searching the nearest farm—only to find nothing. Were the barrels elsewhere? Was it bugged? Did I misunderstand? The game offered no clarity, but it was listed as 1 or 2 levels above mine so I figured it might be in a farm elsewhere in the zone. I kept looking though. The next quest mirrors this problem a little bit.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>The Grain Hunt</li>
</ol>
<p>The second quest seemed simple: gather three grain to make flour. Yet this task took an infuriating 10 whole minutes. The quest vaguely mentioned finding containers on a farm (which one? not specified. There&rsquo;s dozens around), but interactable objects were incredibly sparse. Worse, some of the grain I eventually found wasn’t even located on a farm but at a butcher’s shop! Whether this was poor design or a bug, it felt like the game was actively working against me. I don’t think I can overstate how frustrating this was. I double-checked every farm and field to ensure I hadn’t missed anything. This wasn’t a case of “lol didn’t read.” I’m not exaggerating when I say it took 10 minutes to complete this simple task. I like to believe I&rsquo;m not dumb[citation needed] but this really made me question my intelligence.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Shove Your F****** Bread Up Your F******* Arse.</li>
</ol>
<p>After crafting flour into bread (a process the game handles partially for you, missing an opportunity for tutorialization), I had to go speak to different npc&rsquo;s. While exploring the area beforehand allowed me to see them on the map, this quest revealed a significant UI issue: the quest log and the overlay provided conflicting information. One included the NPCs’ names; the other didn’t. To access basic information, I had to awkwardly rearrange map windows, a clunky and unnecessary hurdle. But why would the overlay contain MORE information than the journal? That&rsquo;s just weird to me. And it was at this point I realized, this isn&rsquo;t just a singular issue. This has been my problem the entire time. Even with the first quest which leads you somewhere with a gigantic arrow pointing at nobody, only to open your map and see you were supposed to go elsewhere. The game does not want you to know where to go.</p>
<p>Combat</p>
<p>While I had high hopes that combat would redeem Corepunk, but it fell short in this area as well. Early fights rely heavily on auto-attacking, offering minimal strategy or engagement. The slow pacing and limited toolkit made encounters feel more like a chore than a challenge. For a game marketed as MOBA-inspired, this was a disappointing experience. While I imagine combat improves as you unlock more skills, the introductory fights failed to leave a strong impression. First impressions matter, and Corepunk squandered its chance to hook me.</p>
<p>Adding to the frustration is the painfully slow recovery process after combat. Healing outside of battle is a grind, either you run back to town (which feels absurd) or burn through consumables (a tolerable but uninspired solution). Since surviving two encounters in a row is nearly impossible early on, the downtime between fights becomes a tedious slog, slamming the brakes on an already slow-paced game.</p>
<p>It Might Pull Through</p>
<p>Despite my frustrations, Corepunk isn’t without merit. The visuals are stunning, and the world-building shows potential. If the developers address these issues, the game could shine in the long run. The combat, too, might become more engaging as players unlock additional abilities. But as it stands, Corepunk fails to live up to its potential.</p>
<p>I’ll give the game another chance at full launch, but I’m no longer holding my breath. With some serious overhauls, Corepunk could still become the game I once dreamed of playing. For now, however, all I can do is hope that they manage to fix its most glaring issues and finds a playerbase so that they can establish themselves and maybe work towards a version of the game that appeals to more people. Until then it serves as a reminder that even the most promising concepts can falter in execution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It doesn&#39;t matter what an MMORPG is.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/it-doesnt-matter-what-an-mmorpg-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/it-doesnt-matter-what-an-mmorpg-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I tried to write an article attempting to define what an MMORPG is after reading &amp;ldquo;What it means to be an MMORPG&amp;rdquo; by Bree Royce, who argues that the definition of an MMORPG is fluid and ever-evolving, making it impossible to define it rigidly. In my original post, I tried to be humorous and wrote, “Trying to define it is a fool’s errand. Today, I am that fool.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week I tried to write an article attempting to define what an MMORPG is after reading &ldquo;What it means to be an MMORPG&rdquo; by Bree Royce, who argues that the definition of an MMORPG is fluid and ever-evolving, making it impossible to define it rigidly. In my original post, I tried to be humorous and wrote, “Trying to define it is a fool’s errand. Today, I am that fool.”</p>
<p>Reader, you have no idea how much those words ring true because I wasted the better part of a weekend trying to make the article work. I made 11 different definitions. When I reached attempt #9 I made a formula for something I called the &ldquo;Social Interaction Possibility Space&rdquo;. In short: it aggregates scores across multiple dimensions of interaction to quantify how social a game is. But in the end it was still subjective because you need to derive your numbers from subjective data. And bullshit in, bullshit out.</p>
<p>The closest I got to something I even remotely agreed with was my final attempt, where I framed it as an &ldquo;online collaborative storytelling medium in a shared world&rdquo;, a bit like TTRPGs.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The genre is characterized by collaborative storytelling, shared persistence, and social engagement, fostering meaningful relationships and shared experiences among players.&rdquo;</p>
<p>As an analogy it has its use, but as a definition it falls short. So I started on attempt #12 by reading &ldquo;Presenting multiple node label support and graph mutability features of the Neo4j Graph Data Science in the Star Wars universe&rdquo;. This kickstarted a two-hour-long side quest trying to take a different approach, then something clicked and I realized I was wrong, and it cannot be done.</p>
<p>After nearly 9 years of hearing people complain about MMORPGs, I thought I had some grasp on what an MMORPG is. I was going to prove just how smart I was. But I wasn&rsquo;t smart, I was arrogant. and because of my arrogance I pissed away a weekend to come to the conclusion that Bree was right and had already handed to me the right answer on a silver platter. That the definition of an MMORPG is dynamic and ever changing.</p>
<p>The question “What is an MMORPG?” is flawed to begin with because it assumes there’s a universal, objective framework for defining a genre that is inherently subjective and deeply influenced by personal experiences, expectations, and cultural context. Like other complex, debated definitions, this question often gets entangled in the values, biases, and agendas of those answering it, rather than revealing an absolute truth.</p>
<p>At the end of the day does it even matter what is and isn&rsquo;t an MMORPG? Does it make a difference if Destiny 2 is objectively an MMORPG? We’re all raiding, running dungeons, competing in PvP matches, and tackling world events. Does the smaller size of Destiny’s zones really disqualify it from being compared to Guild Wars 2, a game where you&rsquo;re raiding, running fractals, competing in structured PvP/WvWvW and participating in open-world events? The DNA is too intertwined to dismiss the game as anything other than an MMORPG to me.</p>
<p>In her article, Bree presented a hierarchical family tree-style graph illustrating the evolution of MMORPGs. While this approach effectively represents historical growth, I personally think for depicting genres I&rsquo;d prefer a system where games are represented as interconnected nodes, with varying degrees of importance. Each game draws inspiration from a diverse range of other games. And perhaps even indicating how much influence they took from a certain game with varying line width.</p>
<p>And all a genre is, is us drawing imaginary lines around collections of games, attempting to group them together in a way that often doesn’t make sense. For instance, what genre is Portal? It’s a game where you solve puzzles that test your spatial and logical reasoning, along with your reflexes, presented as a first-person shooter. Simply labeling it as a puzzle game wouldn’t accurately describe its essence, and calling it a first-person shooter wouldn’t be incorrect either but would feel wrong. So, all we’re doing is limiting how much a developer can change until we no longer recognize it as an MMORPG. So, all that they can do is add another connection and maybe shift that border a tiny bit in the hopes that the genre perhaps moves enough over time.</p>
<p>I saw a screenshot of a Tumblr post the other day by the user Prokopetz about Dungeons &amp; Dragons, which came to mind while making this post that helped me with some insight.</p>
<p>Imagine a person who only consumes Batman-related media. That is, they only watch movies and TV shows that have Batman in them, only read books that are novelisations of Batman media, only play licensed Batman video games, and so forth. This is not so absurd an idea; Batman-related media is sufficiently popular, varied and widespread that restricting one’s media consumption in this way is completely feasible. However, I trust we can agree that if you actually do this, you will be left with very strange ideas about what popular media looks like.</p>
<p>The next step in this analogy is undestanding that if the only tabletop RPG you’re acquainted with is Dungeons &amp; Dragons, you have the same grasp of the tabletop roleplaying hobby as our hypothetical Batman Guy has of popular media.</p>
<p>This is what many people in the MMORPG space have, and at first I felt tempted to call out World of Warcraft but people have this with any game. These games require so much time investment that most players rarely engage with more than one MMORPG at a time. I&rsquo;m willing to bet most people don&rsquo;t even play more than one game at a time, period.</p>
<p>If your preferred MMORPG is Guild Wars 2, and you decide to try World of Warcraft, you might find WoW to feel lifeless because there aren’t any instances of 50 players in a zerg engaging in dynamic events. And if your MMORPG of choice is EVE Online, then most themepark MMORPGs might not even register as a real MMORPG to you. Everything is framed by the game you played first or enjoyed the most.</p>
<p>This phenomenon isn&rsquo;t limited to MMORPGs, think of a concept like Cozy Games. There’s a reason why almost everyone creates farming sims because many people believe that’s what cozy games are. However, they’re all mistaken! In my heart, and objectively, the pinnacle of cozy games is Animal Crossing: Wild World for the Nintendo DS. This is an undeniably correct and unquestionable statement.</p>
<p>So, where does that leave me? After all the definitions, the formulae, and mental gymnastics on a level that would get me to the olympics, I’ve come to realize that the question “What is an MMORPG?” was never the right question to begin with. I’m not even certain if I want to categorize it as a genre anymore; it’s more of a concept similar to cozy games. The question assumes a rigid definition for something that thrives on flexibility, subjectivity, and personal experience.</p>
<p>The right question is one that each of us has to answer for ourselves: “What do you get out of MMORPGs?” For some, it’s about the thrill of raiding with friends. For others, it’s the joy of getting lost in an expansive world, or the satisfaction of mastering intricate systems. For me, it’s the relationships, the sense of shared experience and collaborative storytelling in this virtual world we all inhabit. That’s what keeps me coming back to this genre, no matter how much it changes.</p>
<p>MMORPGs aren’t a static genre. They’re a conversation. A long, sprawling, messy conversation between players and developers, between communities and cultures, between what came before and what’s coming next. Trying to nail down a single definition is like trying to define a conversation by picking out one sentence. It misses the point.</p>
<p>Maybe that’s the beauty of MMORPGs. They resist definition because they’re too big, too diverse, too dynamic to be neatly boxed in. And maybe that’s why we keep playing them, not because we agree on what they are, but because they mean something different to each of us.</p>
<p>Or maybe I&rsquo;m just trying to romanticize this so I feel less bad about having wasted so much time trying to give it a definition anyway.</p>
<p>PS If it doesn&rsquo;t have fishing, it&rsquo;s not an MMORPG.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s the children who are wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/its-the-children-who-are-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 16:05:17 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/its-the-children-who-are-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stood at the front of the classroom, my laptop connected to a carefully crafted presentation on large language models, I felt a wave of pride. This class was my baby, six months of research, experiments, and talking to other experts distilled into a single class. I had practiced my class outside of school with friends both in person and online, they were filled with curiosity and engagement. But with my students? The enthusiasm wasn’t just missing, it felt like it had been sucked out of the room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I stood at the front of the classroom, my laptop connected to a carefully crafted presentation on large language models, I felt a wave of pride. This class was my baby, six months of research, experiments, and talking to other experts distilled into a single class. I had practiced my class outside of school with friends both in person and online, they were filled with curiosity and engagement. But with my students? The enthusiasm wasn’t just missing, it felt like it had been sucked out of the room.</p>
<p>Two students left the classroom early on, leaving their laptops behind. It wasn’t unusual, students sometimes step out for a phone call, a quick smoke (which I don&rsquo;t appreciate but, hey, they&rsquo;re adults), or a bathroom break. I figured they&rsquo;d be back in a few minutes.</p>
<p>They returned an hour and a half later, casually mentioning to a group of students (and to me, as I stood right there) that they had gone to smoke pot. Not just “stepped outside”, but openly admitted to choosing that over my class. I wasn’t angry, just… sad. Sad that my carefully designed lesson, something I hoped they would find interesting after hearing them talk about AI for months, was worth less to them than getting high.</p>
<p>I’m not really letting two students get to me, but the frequency of this kind of disengaged behavior is growing. Another moment that stands out was what I now call &ldquo;the Fortnite incident&rdquo;. It was the first time I got genuinely angry and raised my voice in class, and it surprised even me.</p>
<p>A student called me over during a lecture while still actively playing Fortnite. When I approached, he held up a finger and said, &ldquo;Wait a second&rdquo;. So that he could get to a safe spot in the game.</p>
<p>I couldn’t believe it. My frustration boiled over, and for the first time, I told a student to leave and come back next week. It felt disrespectful, not just to me, but to the entire class.</p>
<p>Then, about a month ago, there was the student who wasn’t even enrolled in my class. She approached me during a break to ask that I not call on her because she wasn’t actually taking the course. Naturally, I asked why she was there, to which she responded, &ldquo;out of interest.&rdquo; For a brief moment, I was happy and a bit flattered, and I said, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re interested in my class, why wouldn&rsquo;t I let you participate in it?&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Oh, I’m not interested in the material,&rdquo; she clarified. &ldquo;I’m interested in my friends.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Dear reader, I was too stunned to respond. I assumed she’d leave when class resumed, but she didn&rsquo;t. And at that point I just lacked the backbone to send her out.</p>
<p>These moments weren’t isolated incidents. From the start of the semester, I noticed a shift in behavior, a lack of engagement, a casual disregard for classroom etiquette, and an overall atmosphere that felt more like high school than higher education.</p>
<p>Halfway through the semester, I realized it wasn’t just the students who needed to change. I needed to change too. My lectures, no matter how carefully crafted, weren’t landing anymore. But with increasing class sizes growing too large for good practical instruction as I can&rsquo;t troubleshoot for 70 students, I felt stuck in a system that wasn’t working.</p>
<p>I won’t pretend I’ve handled this semester perfectly. My frustration with disengaged students started to bleed into how I treated the engaged ones. I lumped them all together, grew angry, and if I’m honest, wanted to win them over in a way. When I failed to get them actively engaged, it just made me feel even more sad. I’m learning to let that go.</p>
<p>Technology isn’t helping either. Large language models, ironically the subject of one of my last class, are also part of the problem. Students no longer ask me questions. Instead they ask AI. It’s faster, easier, and requires less effort than engaging with the material. But the shortcut comes at a cost: a shallow understanding that won’t hold up in the real world, or just straight-up wrong answers, and the time they spend chatting with the AI they are missing on instruction.</p>
<p>I know I can’t go back to the way things were. I need to rethink my approach by crafting in-class assignments that break up lectures and encourage collaboration. Assignments that can’t be outsourced to AI, forcing students to engage with each other and the material in ways only humans can. I&rsquo;ll let you know if I ever figure that one out as my lectures are all in the field of computer science.</p>
<p>I’m also talking to colleagues and students, trying to figure out what works and what doesn’t. Teaching in a changing world is a challenge, but it’s one I’m committed to facing.</p>
<p>Because at the end of the day, maybe the students aren’t entirely wrong. Maybe neither am I. But something needs to change.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>r/MMORPG’s Greatest Hits (and Misses)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/the-best-of-r-mmorpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/the-best-of-r-mmorpg/</guid>
      <description>A (hopefully funny) look at the hatemail, toxicity, and memorable ‘personalities’ we’ve had the pleasure of moderating… so far.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past decade, we’ve compiled a vault of the most &rsquo;legendary&rsquo; commentary r/MMORPG has received. Some gems have been lost to time, but here’s what survived the purge. And just a heads up, not every comment was personally aimed at me; some were crowd-sourced by fellow mods who graciously shared their own &lsquo;fan mail&rsquo; and funny comments they came across.</p>
<p>But I think this poster said it best.</p>
<p>⚠️Trigger Warning
I&rsquo;m not one to quickly write a trigger warning, but there&rsquo;s a lot of racism, homophobia, misogyny and calls for death and suicide to be found in here. Like a LOT.</p>
<p>Ah, my first hatemail! Like a rite of passage, this was the one that officially welcomed me into the glamorous world of internet moderation. Nothing says &lsquo;you&rsquo;re doing great&rsquo; like a well-constructed accusation of a &lsquo;personal vendetta&rsquo; and an &rsquo;emotionally unstable character.&rsquo; It’s almost poetic, really. They didn&rsquo;t care &lsquo;in the slightest,&rsquo; yet here we are, two paragraphs deep.</p>
<p>Rope must have been on sale in the unhinged section, because here we have two people independently deciding that’s the best way to make their point.</p>
<p>Nothing says &lsquo;I’m a well-adjusted human being&rsquo; like rebranding your revolting preferences with a new label. Truly, these are the shining gems of r/MMORPG.</p>
<p>Nothing says teamwork like moderators questioning each other’s taste… and basic survival skills.</p>
<p>The dedication to calling others &lsquo;faggot&rsquo; or &lsquo;gay&rsquo; here is… impressive? Maybe if they put this much effort into learning game mechanics, they’d finally be able to complete an LFR difficulty raid.</p>
<p>I truly hope you’ve found what you’re looking for. May your search be as boundless as your dedication to… custom character adjustments.</p>
<p>Mod chat: where professionalism goes to die, and banter reigns supreme.</p>
<p>Some rants are so gloriously unhinged that it actually pains us a little to remove them.</p>
<p>Sometimes ya&rsquo;ll are just plain weird</p>
<p>If you’re going to throw insults, just know: our mods have comebacks locked and loaded.</p>
<p>After all the rants, the roasts, and the ridiculousness, it’s nice to remember that there’s a little good in every community. We’re lucky to have moments like these.</p>
<p>The tool we use to moderate Reddit rewards us with this little picture of a cat when the report queue is finally empty. It’s like our prize for surviving the chaos.</p>
<p>So here it is, as a reward. Thanks for enduring it all with us!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Dragon Age: The Veilguard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/exploring-dragon-age-the-veilguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/exploring-dragon-age-the-veilguard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve dabbled in Dragon Age before, but never quite made the full commitment. So I went into The Veilguard with cautious excitement. With only around thirteen hours logged so far, I’m just starting to get my bearings. Still, there’s already plenty to talk about, both the good and the things that make me scratch my head a little. From world design to character development and combat, here are my first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve dabbled in Dragon Age before, but never quite made the full commitment. So I went into The Veilguard with cautious excitement. With only around thirteen hours logged so far, I’m just starting to get my bearings. Still, there’s already plenty to talk about, both the good and the things that make me scratch my head a little. From world design to character development and combat, here are my first impressions.</p>
<p>The Characters Need a Little More Roughness</p>
<p>One of the first things that stood out in The Veilguard is the characters. They are certainly memorable, but they almost feel too polished. So far, I’ve met four of them: Bellara, Harding, Lucanis, and Neve. Each of them has a unique personality, but I don’t get the sense that they connect with each other in meaningful ways or push the protagonist, Rook, to grow. They’re good people: morally solid, likable, and they never seem to waver from that. While I appreciate their virtues, I’d like to see more complexity. Lucanis hints at some moral ambiguity, but even his dilemmas feel idealized, framed by concepts of honor and goodness.</p>
<p>What strikes me is how each character seems to exist in their own bubble. Sure, there are some casual quips, but that’s about it. It would be much more compelling if Harding struggled with accepting Lucanis’s demon possession or if Neve occasionally got frustrated with Bellara’s unrelenting positivity. Right now, the lack of meaningful interaction keeps them from feeling like real people with real relationships. Sometimes, it feels like they are caricatures, each with exaggerated traits that don’t lead to any real tension or growth. In a world where curiosity and clashing ideals should naturally create conflict, I’m hoping to see more dramatic collisions between personalities as the story unfolds.</p>
<p>A Half-Open World: Refreshing, but Restrained</p>
<p>The world of The Veilguard opts for a half-open structure. This is different from the endless expanses of Skyrim or the complex, layered maps of Baldur’s Gate 3. It&rsquo;s almost closer to a linear game when you&rsquo;re playing through the story. It’s a choice that has a big impact on pacing, allowing the story to flow more intentionally. Instead of being dragged off into hours of side quests, I find myself tackling shorter, focused activities like a quick puzzle or an optional fight before jumping back into the main story. This format keeps the sense of urgency intact while still leaving room to revisit each zone for side quests later, unlocking larger parts of the map and seeing more of it. It’s refreshing, especially compared to games that end up turning every minor distraction into an hours-long saga.</p>
<p>However, this structure has its downsides. The world, while beautiful, often feels more like a meticulously crafted set than a living, breathing space. Treviso in Antiva, for example, is absolutely stunning, whereas Minrathous’s Dock Town has a grittier, gloomier feel; both are visually distinct but lacking in real interactivity. NPCs don’t react if you bump into them, and many areas are locked without a clear reason. Sometimes it’s hard to tell whether story progression or a puzzle will open the way. I also never feel these places are far away from each other. They feel more like thematic swaps than truly distant locations. And even when there are themes at play I am an observer rather than an actor in the world, there isn&rsquo;t any meaningful way for me to intervene in any conflict outside of dedicated quests, and I am just walking around freely in Minrathous even though I should have a target on my back.</p>
<p>Combat and Gameplay: Striking a Balance</p>
<p>The combat hits a nice balance between action and strategy. I’m playing as a mage, which suits me perfectly as I’ve always loved magic in RPGs. The tactical elements keep things exciting without getting into the overwhelming detail of Baldur’s Gate 3 or the more straightforward approach of Skyrim. The fights that stand out the most are the ones that make me think harder, while the lighter battles let me enjoy the action more casually, making encounters feel distinct. If I had to compare it to another game, I’d say it’s a bit like The Witcher, though it requires less prep work for the bigger fights.</p>
<p>One improvement I’d love to see is the ability to save different builds. Right now, I’m aiming for a spellblade setup, but I also like the deathcaller’s control-oriented abilities. A feature that let me save and switch between builds and armor would make experimenting much more enjoyable.</p>
<p>The Story: Making Lore Accessible</p>
<p>The story pacing feels well-balanced so far, but as someone who isn’t deeply familiar with previous Dragon Age games, I find myself wanting the lore to be more accessible. The codex entries are helpful, but they can pull me out of the game when I need to read them in detail. A simple fix would be narrated codex entries that I could listen to while exploring. I’d also love something like Destiny 2’s books, a way to gather pieces of lore in order and collect those I want to dive into more deeply. Maybe vendors could even sell those missing pieces, adding an extra layer to exploration. Or, hear me out, give me a mobile app. Yes, I know mobile tie-in apps typically suck, but if I have to read, at least let me read when I want to read, not when I want to play a video game. Reading the wiki isn&rsquo;t the same.</p>
<p>Dialogue choices are impactful, and I’ve already experienced some touching moments. One of my favorites was encouraging Harding to see her magic as a gift instead of something to fear. It’s these smaller, intimate choices that feel the most meaningful, and I hope they happen more often. I know these moments take a lot of writing effort, but they are what make RPG storytelling so special: the sense of being genuinely invested in the growth of my companions.</p>
<p>Where It Stands So Far</p>
<p>Overall, Dragon Age: The Veilguard is a polished experience that feels modern while staying true to its RPG roots. The half-open world is a welcome change, allowing for a focused kind of gameplay that’s hard to find in today’s sprawling, distraction-heavy games. It feels like BioWare decided to refine what makes a game immersive rather than expanding endlessly just for the sake of scale.</p>
<p>The Veilguard strikes a good balance for newcomers and RPG veterans alike, though I expect some players may resist the changes just because they’re different. Even so, I’m excited to see how the characters evolve, and I’m hoping they can break free from their archetypes and start interacting in more real, messy ways. If BioWare can keep refining this mix of action, strategy, and character-driven choices, The Veilguard could easily become one of my favorite games of the year. I’m having a blast, and I still can’t quite believe EA published it. There are no microtransactions, it doesn&rsquo;t require the EA Play launcher, nor does it require an online connection to play a single-player game. All this and more in 2024.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Gave Away $232,772.2 in Free Advertising on r/MMORPG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/why-i-gave-away-232-772-2-in-free-advertising-on-r-mmorpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/why-i-gave-away-232-772-2-in-free-advertising-on-r-mmorpg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Story Behind r/MMORPG&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;r/MMORPG is a subreddit with its share of challenges, rough edges, and the occasional bad apple in both the community and the moderation team. However, what truly defines it is its dedicated community. These are people who love a very specific niche of gaming, coming to Reddit to discuss, discover, and share their passion, even to hate on games they dislike, which is a different kind of love, I suppose. This combination, though, makes the subreddit a bit of a minefield for developers. Even a whiff of positivity is sometimes dismissed as astroturfing, and many devs struggle to figure out how to engage without crossing invisible lines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Story Behind r/MMORPG</p>
<p>r/MMORPG is a subreddit with its share of challenges, rough edges, and the occasional bad apple in both the community and the moderation team. However, what truly defines it is its dedicated community. These are people who love a very specific niche of gaming, coming to Reddit to discuss, discover, and share their passion, even to hate on games they dislike, which is a different kind of love, I suppose. This combination, though, makes the subreddit a bit of a minefield for developers. Even a whiff of positivity is sometimes dismissed as astroturfing, and many devs struggle to figure out how to engage without crossing invisible lines.</p>
<p>Yet, it&rsquo;s hard to ignore the platform when r/MMORPG has over 50 million views annually and an average of 635k unique visitors per month, and it&rsquo;s still growing. For indie developers, this audience is too important to pass up as it is their core audience.</p>
<p>I joined the moderator team more than eight years ago, and six years ago, I became the subreddit’s owner. Well, &ldquo;administrator&rdquo; is a better term, after all, this is Reddit, not my private domain, and any value we create here ultimately belongs to the platform of which we see no return. Meanwhile Reddit is making deals selling user content to AI companies. But I’ve tried to make a positive impact where I can to improve the community for the people who enjoy it.</p>
<p>The Developer Spotlight program is one such initiative I introduced to bridge the gap between game developers and the r/MMORPG community. It allows developers to showcase their projects, gather valuable feedback, and engage with our passionate audience.</p>
<p>How the Spotlight Came to Be</p>
<p>Not many know this, but I used to work at an indie dev studio. Thankfully, I was an employee rather than one of the founders, but I still saw firsthand the struggles of promoting a game on a shoestring budget. It became clear that devs needed more opportunities to connect with audiences without paying an arm and a leg, and ideally, these opportunities would benefit everyone involved. To put things into perspective: GamesRadar charges about $5,000 for ads, estimating roughly 3,000 wishlists from the campaign. Meanwhile, OTK Media, the company representing streamers like Asmongold and Sodapoppin, charges $75,000 to showcase your game during their winter expo, and a 60-second ad during that same event costs $10,000. People deserve to be paid for their services, but for small developers, $75,000 could represent a year’s worth of income, something most simply can&rsquo;t justify spending.</p>
<p>That’s what the r/MMORPG Developer Spotlight was designed to do: offer a week of prime exposure where devs could introduce their projects to our community, share insights, and foster conversations, all without spending a cent. In return, we’d get great content for the subreddit, and our community would learn about upcoming games. It’s hard to beat free advertising, especially when it comes with a click-through rate of around 30%. Many of these spotlights have sparked articles, conversations, and lasting interest. By my own calculations we provide approximately $4,952.60 worth of free advertisement per spotlight. If you want to check my math, or check out what I estimate the value would be depending on a different CPM you can do so here.</p>
<p>We’ve had some standout examples over the years. Corepunk’s spotlight drew significant attention, as did Profane. One smaller project even managed to attract a bigger development team thanks to the exposure. It&rsquo;s moments like these that remind me why offering the platform for free has been a privilege, even if the community isn&rsquo;t always 100% supportive.</p>
<p>Challenges and Limitations</p>
<p>Of course, the spotlight isn’t without its flaws. The biggest limitation? Me. Organizing these spotlights takes time and energy, and I haven’t been able to delegate the workload effectively, as not many people are interested in working for free. Burnout is real, and sometimes I just can&rsquo;t find the time.</p>
<p>There’s also the challenge of making judgment calls, deciding which projects to feature and which to decline. Is a solo dev’s game a passion project or a thinly-veiled scam? I’ve denied games because I didn’t trust the developer, and I’ve tried to systematize the decision-making process, even going so far as to create a points system at one time. But in the end, it’s all subjective.</p>
<p>Then there’s Reddit itself. We don’t own the platform; we’re subject to its rules and limitations. I can’t set up a newsletter, add new functionality, tweak the CSS, or even send notifications, all things that could help us improve the spotlight program. Our reach and growth are ultimately limited by Reddit’s decisions.</p>
<p>To make things more complicated, Reddit’s mobile interface is taking over, which makes it even harder to highlight the content we want to feature. It’s something we’re still trying to work around.</p>
<p>The Future of the Spotlight, r/MMORPG, and My Place in It</p>
<p>I want to kick off another big round of developer spotlights, ideally with new developers, and collaborate more closely to create engaging content. As for the subreddit itself, it&rsquo;s doing well: we’ve grown significantly over the past year, with views increasing to 50.5 million and a steady rise in unique visitors and subscribers.</p>
<p>But as we move forward, I’ve been questioning my own place here. By 2026, I’ll have been involved with r/MMORPG for ten years, and I’m starting to think it might be time for me to step aside. There are others who could do an amazing job. And I’ll admit, I’m scared of letting go, scared of losing the industry contacts, scared of being just another player again. It’s something I’ve been mulling over for the past two years, and by the ten-year mark, I’ll have made my decision.</p>
<p>Closing Thoughts</p>
<p>What a roundabout way to announce I might be stepping down, all while just wanting to highlight the spotlight program and give a bit of context! But I’m genuinely proud of what we’ve built here. I’ve met incredible people along the way, and I hope I’ve made a difference, even if the community doesn’t always appreciate my efforts. I’m not looking for validation anymore; I just want to keep making things better, for however long I&rsquo;m still here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to coffee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/ode-to-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 10:31:31 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/ode-to-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee, thou art my tempestuous companion, both invigorating and soothing. When my mornings are heavy with languor, you change my frame of mind. Your warmth runs through me, awakening my senses and shaking me from my comatose state, with your rich, redolent floral aroma and your lustrous dark color. It feels as though I could reach out and touch velvet itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is comfort in the ritual of your preparation, the whirring of the grinder, the bubbling brew, and the rising perfume that fills my small kitchen while the day&amp;rsquo;s first light catches on the steam that rises from the cup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, thou art my tempestuous companion, both invigorating and soothing. When my mornings are heavy with languor, you change my frame of mind. Your warmth runs through me, awakening my senses and shaking me from my comatose state, with your rich, redolent floral aroma and your lustrous dark color. It feels as though I could reach out and touch velvet itself.</p>
<p>There is comfort in the ritual of your preparation, the whirring of the grinder, the bubbling brew, and the rising perfume that fills my small kitchen while the day&rsquo;s first light catches on the steam that rises from the cup.</p>
<p>For a moment while waiting, as I stretch and yawn, feeling the world drift by, I see my deep, tangled thoughts unravel. For just a moment, the world outside the kitchen ceases to exist, and there is only you and I.</p>
<p>You are both the comforting embrace that cradles me and the spark that ignites me; a codependent yet undeniably beautiful bond. Here&rsquo;s to you, coffee, the magic that brings the mundane to life, one glorious cup at a time.</p>
<p>So, to whom it may concern: Get the coffee machine fixed, or I will start invoicing my daily trips to Madmum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woolfe: A Belgian Fairytale with a Dark Twist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/woolfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 16:06:23 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/woolfe/</guid>
      <description>Belgian-made games don’t often make waves, but Woolfe from developer Grin has the potential to change that. With a mix of dark fairytales and rich visuals, it offers a promising glimpse into what indie games can achieve.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>⚠️Disclaimer
This article was first published in the November 2013 issue of G Van Games magazine, authored by me. In wanting to republish my earlier work I&rsquo;ve taken the opportunity to refine it and get rid of the word count restrictions the print version had. Think of it as a remastered version rather than a straightforward translation.</p>
<p>While the core content remains unchanged, certain sections have been polished to enhance clarity and flow. Please note, however, that no new information or updates have been added since the article’s original release.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, I had the chance to visit Grin’s studio in Antwerp to preview their latest project, Woolfe. It was a typical gray day in the city, setting an unintentionally fitting mood for the dark fairytale world the team is creating. While my time with the game was limited, I left with a solid understanding of the atmosphere Grin is aiming to capture, and the challenges they face as a small studio trying to deliver something special.</p>
<p>First Impressions: Atmosphere Over Mechanics</p>
<p>The first thing that stands out about Woolfe is its visual style. The game leans heavily on a dark, fairytale-inspired aesthetic, with clear nods to the Little Red Riding Hood story. The tone is grim, yet maintains a certain charm, using familiar fairytale elements in a way that feels fresh without becoming cliché. For an indie game, the polish on the visuals is impressive, even at this stage.</p>
<p>However, it’s important to note that I didn’t get much time to dive into gameplay mechanics. The demo I played was an early build, and many of the systems, from combat to puzzle-solving, are still being refined. It wouldn’t be fair to judge the gameplay based on this short experience, as what I saw was likely far from the finished product. What was clear, though, is that the team is focusing on creating a cohesive world first, and worrying about perfecting mechanics later.</p>
<p>Behind the Scenes: The Reality of Indie Development</p>
<p>While the game’s visuals grabbed my attention, the visit was also a reminder of the realities of indie game development. Grin is a relatively small studio, founded in 2002, and most of their previous work was focused on smaller, browser-based projects. Woolfe represents their first big leap into a larger, more ambitious project. Naturally, this comes with challenges.</p>
<p>During the visit, the team openly discussed the balancing act required to make a game like Woolfe with limited resources. Funding through initiatives like the VAF Game Fund has been crucial to the project’s progress, but indie development is always a race against time and budget. It’s clear that the developers are passionate, but that alone isn’t always enough to guarantee success. Watching the team juggle creative ambitions with the practical constraints of a small studio was a reminder of how difficult it can be to get a game like Woolfe off the ground.</p>
<p>What Lies Ahead for Woolfe</p>
<p>As this was an early build, there’s still much about Woolfe that remains uncertain. The developers themselves admitted they’re still finding the right balance between narrative, gameplay, and style. What I did play showed promise, but also left a lot of open questions. It’s one thing to craft a compelling atmosphere, but integrating that with satisfying gameplay is a challenge that many indie games face.</p>
<p>The combat and platforming elements I briefly experienced felt serviceable, though I didn’t spend enough time with them to get a real sense of depth. It will be interesting to see how these systems evolve as the game moves closer to release.</p>
<p>A Measured Outlook</p>
<p>It’s easy to get swept up in the excitement of seeing a game in development, but Woolfe is still very much a work in progress. What Grin has shown so far is promising, particularly in terms of visual direction and atmosphere. That said, indie development is unpredictable, and many hurdles remain between the current build and a polished final product.</p>
<p>Grin’s ambitions are clear, and they’re aiming to make a real impact with this title. Whether Woolfe can rise above the challenges and deliver on its potential will depend on how well the team can balance the various elements they’re still refining.</p>
<p>The Takeaway?</p>
<p>There’s no denying Woolfe has potential. The world Grin is building is visually engaging, and the concept of a darker, reimagined fairytale has definite appeal. But, as with any indie game in its early stages, there are still a lot of unknowns. What Grin has right now is a promising foundation, but the real test will be whether they can turn that foundation into a cohesive and enjoyable game by the time it’s ready for release.</p>
<p>For now, Woolfe is a project worth keeping an eye on, but it’s best approached with cautious optimism.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tom Waits, Closing Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/tom-waits-closing-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:17:42 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/tom-waits-closing-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Closing Time&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Originally, I was going to pick a thrash metal album for this article, but a sleepless night due to the sweltering heat left me craving something that would mellow me the fuck out. So, I ventured into a genre I wasn’t very familiar with: blues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eventually stumbling onto “Closing Time” by Tom Waits I sat down to start to listen while watching the sun rise. Which perfectly accompanied the opening track “Ol’55”, which sounded exactly like what I needed. Its melancholic yet sweet melody, paired with relatable lyrics about driving home after a one-night stand as the sun rises, evoked a sweet sounding nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Closing Time</p>
<p>Originally, I was going to pick a thrash metal album for this article, but a sleepless night due to the sweltering heat left me craving something that would mellow me the fuck out. So, I ventured into a genre I wasn’t very familiar with: blues.</p>
<p>Eventually stumbling onto “Closing Time” by Tom Waits I sat down to start to listen while watching the sun rise. Which perfectly accompanied the opening track “Ol’55”, which sounded exactly like what I needed. Its melancholic yet sweet melody, paired with relatable lyrics about driving home after a one-night stand as the sun rises, evoked a sweet sounding nostalgia.</p>
<p>The album features music that might not get stuck in your head but is made to be thoroughly enjoyable in the moment. The lyrics weave narratives without being overly complicated, a refreshing change from yesterday’s trip with MGMT. Maybe it’s the sleep deprivation making me more open to actually feeling something, but the album effectively evokes the emotions Tom sings about. Albeit those emotions primarily being “somber” and “serene” but in a way that can uncloud you from intensely negative sentiment. Not all songs fit this mold; for instance, “Lonely” is literally about being lonely, with 27% of the lyrics consisting of the word “lonely.” However, even here this track doesn’t convey an overwhelming sadness but rather a low, persistent melancholy. Am I reading too much into it? Possibly. But then “Ice Cream Man” comes along, a more upbeat song about seduction, or so I assume. It’s a bit quirky.</p>
<p>Overall, Tom Waits’ “Closing Time” is a fantastic album filled with emotionally driven songs about life, desire, love, and loss. It’s impressive how the album balances depth with a sense of not taking itself too seriously, both lyrically and musically.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: This article was originally published on my GitHub Pages blog. Minor edits may have been made for clarity and formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve got a friend (that wants to take your money) in me.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/youve-got-a-friend-that-wants-to-take-your-money-in-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:12:39 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/youve-got-a-friend-that-wants-to-take-your-money-in-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear tech bro’s,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can we just stop with this late-stage capitalist nonsense of creating inferior products to replace things we already have? It’s like a strategy to erode our reliance on actual skills and tools, all to charge us a monthly fee for something we can already do with minimal effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, a tech company has launched a product aimed at replacing the idea of friends as a support system. It introduces a constant, chatty presence in your life, making sure you never have a moment of peace. Because god forbid you form an actual thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear tech bro’s,</p>
<p>Can we just stop with this late-stage capitalist nonsense of creating inferior products to replace things we already have? It’s like a strategy to erode our reliance on actual skills and tools, all to charge us a monthly fee for something we can already do with minimal effort.</p>
<p>This week, a tech company has launched a product aimed at replacing the idea of friends as a support system. It introduces a constant, chatty presence in your life, making sure you never have a moment of peace. Because god forbid you form an actual thought.</p>
<p>Before we dive deeper, let’s watch the product video together:</p>
<p>What the actual fuck did we just witness?</p>
<p>This device features an always-on microphone(I assume, the video shows it both ways) that texts you comments on your actions, responds to nonsensical remarks, makes judgments, and interrupts your activities—basically, it pretends to be an important figure in your life while actually being invasive and annoying.</p>
<p>We often throw around Orwell’s name whenever something feels dystopian, but in this case, it seems apt. Orwell would probably be alarmed by such a device—a “friend” that monitors your every move, potentially manipulates your perceptions of reality as it is happening, and records your interactions. It’s like a creepy version of Big Brother masquerading as a&hellip; well&hellip; friend.</p>
<p>The concept video is clearly overblown marketing for what is essentially just a wrapper around chatgpt. The claim that it’s been in development for years is laughable - The product is so underbaked and obviously in the concept stage. How can the AI make a comment on a show you’re watching if you had to press a button to talk to it afterwards? Is it recording your screen? Audio analysis? How does the AI have opinions on a show? Is this curated by other people? Does the AI know your preferences and says things to align with how you think? That comment the guy got about losing the game. Yeah trash talk is funny, but imagine getting that message when your confidence is low.</p>
<p>It’s, well, a friend — an AI friend that can go with you anywhere, experience things with you, and just be there with you all the time. “It’s very supportive, very validating, it’ll encourage your ideas,” Schiffmann Interview with “The Verge”</p>
<p>A friend? No. It’s not. People get lonely. I’ve been there myself. But having an AI around your neck that says “You go girl, eat that cheeseburger!” isn’t solving loneliness. It’s making it worse by teaching people to expect from humans what they get from an AI in terms of communication and what support looks like, thereby unlearning real coping mechanisms.</p>
<p>I suspect all the processing happens in a mobile app, and the necklace is just a Bluetooth microphone. At least if that’s true, you might be able to repurpose the device when the company inevitably goes under.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, billions will be sunk into gadgets like this, which will eventually end up in landfills. All this while we bemoan the planet’s burning state, with AI set to use more energy by 2026 than Japan, a country of 125 million people. All thanks to unchecked corporate greed.</p>
<p>In 1979 IBM said in a presentation</p>
<p>“A computer can never be held accountable, therefore a computer must never make a management decision” -</p>
<p>So to end this rant I’d like to steal that quote and make it my own.</p>
<p>“A computer isn’t a fucking person, and therefore can’t be your fucking friend.”</p>
<p>Disclaimer: This article was originally published on my GitHub Pages blog. Minor edits may have been made for clarity and formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MGMT, Oracular Spectacular</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/mgmt-oracular-spectacular/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:05:51 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/mgmt-oracular-spectacular/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oracular Spectacular&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I often wonder how creative projects like this come together. Was there a grand vision, or did things naturally evolve into the final product? This question lingers especially when considering the choice to open the album with “Time to Pretend.” The song cynically mocks the clichés of rockstar success, suggesting that even in our dream scenarios, reality still hits hard. At least, that’s my interpretation. Unlike Rage Against the Machine, which delivers its messages very directly, or Marian Hill, which seems to lack message, MGMT layers their songs with meaning and metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oracular Spectacular</p>
<p>I often wonder how creative projects like this come together. Was there a grand vision, or did things naturally evolve into the final product? This question lingers especially when considering the choice to open the album with “Time to Pretend.” The song cynically mocks the clichés of rockstar success, suggesting that even in our dream scenarios, reality still hits hard. At least, that’s my interpretation. Unlike Rage Against the Machine, which delivers its messages very directly, or Marian Hill, which seems to lack message, MGMT layers their songs with meaning and metaphor.</p>
<p>“Weekend Wars” is open to multiple interpretations. Is it about the fleeting nature of weekends? A quest for self-discovery? I’m not entirely sure, but that’s part of the charm. “The Youth” feels like a call to break generational cycles, while “Electric Feel” could be about the thrill of a new attraction, sex, or even the effects of drugs. MGMT leaves these interpretations open. This interpretative aspect acts almost like a Rorschach test, revealing as much about the listener as the music itself. For example, “Kids” seems to explore how we are shaped, often negatively, by the actions of those around us. But other people might say its about life, and how it’s fleeting so its better to not be passive in your observation of it.</p>
<p>A criticism I had with my previous reviews, particularly with Marian Hill, is that not all songs manage to have their own identity. This is not the case with MGMT’s debut album. Every song on “Oracular Spectacular” stands on its own, each with a unique character. While some tracks may be more memorable than others, there are no bad songs on the album — a hill I’m willing to die on. If I have to say something negative its that some songs might feel a bit too long. But given the trend of shortening tracks in order to appeal to for short-form video content virality, I’d rather have a song that perhaps overstays its welcome than one that doesn’t have enough time to develop.</p>
<p>“Oracular Spectacular” is a true gift. Its expertly crafted, sometimes psychedelic synthesizer sounds, paired with robust vocals and often impenetrable lyrics, create a 40-minute journey that captivates from start to finish.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: This article was originally published on my GitHub Pages blog. Minor edits may have been made for clarity and formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marian Hill, Act One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/marian-hill-act-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:04:38 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/marian-hill-act-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Act One&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marian Hill is a duo I was familiar with primarily because of the song “Down,” which opens this album. “Down” is a standout track with its catchy chopped vocals and trap beat, and it’s no surprise it’s a favourite of mine on Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I continued through the album, I was initially concerned that the rest of the tracks might not match the high bar set by “Down.” However, “Talk to Me” quickly eased that worry with its intriguing saxophone sounds, setting a promising tone for the album that it ultimately could not entirely maintain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Act One</p>
<p>Marian Hill is a duo I was familiar with primarily because of the song “Down,” which opens this album. “Down” is a standout track with its catchy chopped vocals and trap beat, and it’s no surprise it’s a favourite of mine on Apple Music.</p>
<p>As I continued through the album, I was initially concerned that the rest of the tracks might not match the high bar set by “Down.” However, “Talk to Me” quickly eased that worry with its intriguing saxophone sounds, setting a promising tone for the album that it ultimately could not entirely maintain.</p>
<p>Rather than focusing on lyrical depth, the album places its emphasis on creating a mood and incorporating unique sounds into each song. For example, “I Know Why” features a distinctive waterdrop effect. However, some tracks take a while to find their groove, and by the time they do, they’re nearly over. “Good” is a prime example, leaving you wanting more just as it hits its stride.</p>
<p>The vocals often serve as another instrument, blending seamlessly with the music, making it clear that the focus is more on the atmosphere than the lyrics themselves. Occasionally, though, the lyrics and music feel out of sync, as if they were crafted separately without fully meshing. This can range from mildly annoying to quite distracting, possibly due to a mixing issue.</p>
<p>The album maintains a laid-back yet engaging mood with a slightly dark edge. Marian Hill clearly aims to entertain, guiding listeners through various musical ideas. The experience somewhat dampened by weak vocal performance. Overall, “Act One” opens strong, falters somewhat in the middle, but manages to close on a high note. Highlights include “Down,” “Take Your Time,” “I Want You,” and “Mistaken.”</p>
<p>Disclaimer: This article was originally published on my GitHub Pages blog. Minor edits may have been made for clarity and formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rage Against The Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/rage-against-the-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 07:02:13 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts-copy/rage-against-the-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album: Rage Against The Machine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m not a fan of eponymous album names. Having to write “Rage Against the Machine” twice in a row—and needing to clarify that it wasn’t a mistake with the “Album:” prefix—only adds to my dislike. The fact that they technically have two eponymous albums doesn’t change my opinion. I’ll always be a hater at heart. But this might not be such a big issue for this album because Rage Against the Machine is a justifiably angry album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Album: Rage Against The Machine</p>
<p>I’m not a fan of eponymous album names. Having to write “Rage Against the Machine” twice in a row—and needing to clarify that it wasn’t a mistake with the “Album:” prefix—only adds to my dislike. The fact that they technically have two eponymous albums doesn’t change my opinion. I’ll always be a hater at heart. But this might not be such a big issue for this album because Rage Against the Machine is a justifiably angry album.</p>
<p>Rage Against The Machine’s Rage Against the Machine should be an extremely contemporary album that points a finger at the issues the band identified at the time. However, as time has shown repeatedly, we’re all stuck on this hellride, and some of us are actively trying to get off. As a result, the album isn’t just contemporary to 1992; it’s relevant today as well.</p>
<p>“Landlords and power whores, on my people, they took turns. Dispute the suits, I ignite and then watch ‘em burn.”</p>
<p>These lyrics feel as relevant today as they did back then—at least, I assume so, since I wasn’t born when the album came out. <del>Hi Bert, feel old?</del></p>
<p>Even Killing In The Name is as pertinent as ever, especially in light of yet another black person being murdered by the police for merely existing.</p>
<p>The album is filled with lyrics that hit as hard today as they did back then. The music itself also hits just as hard, with riffs that get stuck in your head and what I assume is very experimental sounds. Proving that good music stays good.</p>
<p>Liked</p>
<ul>
<li>Unique soundscape, with lots of electric guitar played by someone who is an absolute master of their craft. I genuinely didn’t know someone could be that skilled at an instrument.</li>
<li>They obviously had fun writing the music, and you can hear that in every aspect.</li>
</ul>
<p>Disliked</p>
<ul>
<li>Some songs don’t carve out their own unique musical identities and can blend together.</li>
</ul>
<p>Conclusion</p>
<p>I don’t like giving scores, so I won’t. A great album that, unfortunately, remains as relevant today as it was back then.
This album should be mandatory listening in 2024.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: This article was originally published on my GitHub Pages blog. Minor edits may have been made for clarity and formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
