<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-31T09:41:27+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Protobear</title><subtitle>A place where Marnick writes down some of his personal opinions. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tom Waits, Closing Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/31/Tom-Waits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tom Waits, Closing Time" /><published>2024-07-31T09:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-31T09:30:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/31/Tom-Waits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/31/Tom-Waits.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="tom-waits">Tom Waits</h2>
<h3 id="closing-time">Closing Time</h3>

<p>Originally, I was going to pick a thrash metal album for this article, but a sleepless night due to the sweltering heat left me craving something that would mellow me the fuck out. So, I ventured into a genre I wasn’t very familiar with: blues.</p>

<p>Eventually stumbling onto “Closing Time” by Tom Waits I sat down to start to listen while watching the sun rise. Which perfectly accompanied the opening track “Ol’55”, which sounded exactly like what I needed. Its melancholic yet sweet melody, paired with relatable lyrics about driving home after a one-night stand as the sun rises, evoked a mellifluous<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> nostalgia.</p>

<p>The album features music that might not get stuck in your head but is made to be thoroughly enjoyable in the moment. The lyrics weave narratives without being overly complicated, a refreshing change from <a href="https://protobear.github.io/music/2024/07/30/MGMT.html">yesterday’s trip with MGMT</a>. Maybe it’s the sleep deprivation making me more open to actually feeling something, but the album effectively evokes the emotions Tom sings about. Albeit those emotions primarily being “somber” and “serene” but in a way that can uncloud you from intensely negative sentiment. Not all songs fit this mold; for instance, “Lonely” is literally about being lonely, with 27% of the lyrics consisting of the word “lonely.” However, even here this track doesn’t convey an overwhelming sadness but rather a low, persistent melancholy. Am I reading too much into it? Possibly. But then “Ice Cream Man” comes along, a more upbeat song about seduction, or so I assume. It’s a bit quirky.</p>

<p>Overall, Tom Waits’ “Closing Time” is a fantastic album filled with emotionally driven songs about life, desire, love, and loss. It’s impressive how the album balances depth with a sense of not taking itself too seriously, both lyrically and musically.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>(of a sound) pleasingly smooth and musical to hear.  - I have no clue if I used this word correctly. But I’m rolling with it anyway. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Waits Closing Time]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You’ve got a friend (that wants to take your money) in me.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rant/2024/07/30/friend.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You’ve got a friend (that wants to take your money) in me." /><published>2024-07-30T20:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T20:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rant/2024/07/30/friend</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rant/2024/07/30/friend.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey tech bro’s,</p>

<p>Can we just stop with this late-stage capitalist nonsense of creating inferior products to replace things we already have? It’s like a strategy to erode our reliance on actual skills and tools, all to charge us a monthly fee for something we can already do with minimal effort.</p>

<p>This week, a tech company has launched a product aimed at replacing the idea of friends as a support system. It introduces a constant, chatty presence in your life, making sure you never have a moment of peace. Because god forbid you form an actual thought.</p>

<p>Before we dive deeper, let’s watch the product video:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O_Q1hoEhfk4?si=B09Rt25ygPgVRDpy" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>What the actual fuck did we just witness?</p>

<p>This device features an always-on microphone(I assume, the video shows it both ways) that texts you comments on your actions, responds to nonsensical remarks, makes judgments, and interrupts your activities—basically, it pretends to be an important figure in your life while actually being invasive and annoying.</p>

<p>We often throw around Orwell’s name whenever something feels dystopian, but in this case, it seems apt. Orwell would probably be alarmed by such a device—a “friend” that monitors your every move, potentially manipulates your perceptions of reality as it is happening, and records your interactions. It’s like a creepy version of Big Brother masquerading as a buddy.</p>

<p>The concept video is clearly overblown marketing for what is essentially just a wrapper around chatgpt. The claim that it’s been in development for years is laughable - The product is so underbaked and obviously in the concept stage. How can the AI make a comment on a show you’re watching if you had to press a button to talk to it afterwards? Is it recording your screen? Audio analysis? How does the AI have opinions on a show? Is this curated by other people? Does the AI know your preferences and says things to align with how you think? That comment the guy got about losing the game. Yeah trash talk is funny, but imagine getting that message when your confidence is low.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s, well, a friend — an AI friend that can go with you anywhere, experience things with you, and just be there with you all the time. “It’s very supportive, very validating, it’ll encourage your ideas,” Schiffmann 
<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/30/24207029/friend-ai-companion-gadget"><em>Interview with “The Verge”</em></a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>A friend? No. It’s not. People get lonely. I’ve been there myself. But having an AI around your neck that says <em>“You go girl, eat that cheeseburger!”</em> isn’t solving loneliness. It’s making it worse by teaching people to expect from humans what they get from an AI in terms of communication and what support looks like, thereby unlearning real coping mechanisms.</p>

<p>I suspect all the processing happens in a mobile app, and the necklace is just a Bluetooth microphone. At least if that’s true, you might be able to repurpose the device when the company inevitably goes under.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, billions will be sunk into gadgets like this, which will eventually end up in landfills. All this while we bemoan the planet’s burning state, with AI set to use more energy by 2026 than Japan, a country of 125 million people. All thanks to unchecked corporate greed.</p>

<p>In 1979 IBM said in a presentation</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“A computer can never be held accountable, therefore a computer must never make a management decision” -</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So to end this rant I’d like to steal that quote and make it my own.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“A computer isn’t a fucking person, and therefore can’t be your fucking friend.”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="rant" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey tech bro’s,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MGMT, Oracular Spectacular</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/30/MGMT.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MGMT, Oracular Spectacular" /><published>2024-07-30T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/30/MGMT</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/30/MGMT.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="mgmt">MGMT</h2>
<h3 id="oracular-spectacular">Oracular Spectacular</h3>

<p>I often wonder how creative projects like this come together. Was there a grand vision, or did things naturally evolve into the final product? This question lingers especially when considering the choice to open the album with “Time to Pretend.” The song cynically mocks the clichés of rockstar success, suggesting that even in our dream scenarios, reality still hits hard. At least, that’s my interpretation. Unlike <a href="https://protobear.github.io/music/2024/07/29/Rage-Against-The-Machine.html">Rage Against the Machine</a>, which delivers its messages very directly, or <a href="https://protobear.github.io/music/2024/07/30/Marian-Hill.html">Marian Hill</a>, which seems to lack message, MGMT layers their songs with meaning and metaphor.</p>

<p>“Weekend Wars” is open to multiple interpretations. Is it about the fleeting nature of weekends? A quest for self-discovery? I’m not entirely sure, but that’s part of the charm. “The Youth” feels like a call to break generational cycles, while “Electric Feel” could be about the thrill of a new attraction, sex, or even the effects of drugs. MGMT leaves these interpretations open. This interpretative aspect acts almost like a Rorschach test, revealing as much about the listener as the music itself. For example, “Kids” seems to explore how we are shaped, often negatively, by the actions of those around us. But other people might say its about life, and how it’s fleeting so its better to not be passive in your observation of it.</p>

<p>A criticism I had with my previous reviews, particularly with Marian Hill, is that not all songs manage to have their own identity. This is not the case with MGMT’s debut album. Every song on “Oracular Spectacular” stands on its own, each with a unique character. While some tracks may be more memorable than others, there are no bad songs on the album — a hill I’m willing to die on. If I have to say something negative its that some songs might feel a bit too long. But given the trend of shortening tracks in order to appeal to for short-form video content virality, I’d rather have a song that perhaps overstays its welcome than one that doesn’t have enough time to develop.</p>

<p>“Oracular Spectacular” is a true gift. Its expertly crafted, sometimes psychedelic synthesizer sounds, paired with robust vocals and often impenetrable lyrics, create a 40-minute journey that captivates from start to finish.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MGMT Oracular Spectacular]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Marian Hill, Act One</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/30/Marian-Hill.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marian Hill, Act One" /><published>2024-07-30T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/30/Marian-Hill</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/30/Marian-Hill.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="marian-hill">Marian Hill</h1>
<h2 id="act-one">Act One</h2>

<p>Marian Hill is a duo I was familiar with primarily because of the song “Down,” which opens this album. “Down” is a standout track with its catchy chopped vocals and trap beat, and it’s no surprise it’s a favourite of mine on Apple Music.</p>

<p>As I continued through the album, I was initially concerned that the rest of the tracks might not match the high bar set by “Down.” However, “Talk to Me” quickly eased that worry with its intriguing saxophone sounds, setting a promising tone for the album that it ultimately could not entirely maintain.</p>

<p>Rather than focusing on lyrical depth, the album places its emphasis on creating a mood and incorporating unique sounds into each song. For example, “I Know Why” features a distinctive waterdrop effect. However, some tracks take a while to find their groove, and by the time they do, they’re nearly over. “Good” is a prime example, leaving you wanting more just as it hits its stride.</p>

<p>The vocals often serve as another instrument, blending seamlessly with the music, making it clear that the focus is more on the atmosphere than the lyrics themselves. Occasionally, though, the lyrics and music feel out of sync, as if they were crafted separately without fully meshing. This can range from mildly annoying to quite distracting, possibly due to a mixing issue.</p>

<p>The album maintains a laid-back yet engaging mood with a slightly dark edge. Marian Hill clearly aims to entertain, guiding listeners through various musical ideas. The experience somewhat dampened by weak vocal performance. Overall, “Act One” opens strong, falters somewhat in the middle, but manages to close on a high note. Highlights include “Down,” “Take Your Time,” “I Want You,” and “Mistaken.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marian Hill Act One Marian Hill is a duo I was familiar with primarily because of the song “Down,” which opens this album. “Down” is a standout track with its catchy chopped vocals and trap beat, and it’s no surprise it’s a favourite of mine on Apple Music. As I continued through the album, I was initially concerned that the rest of the tracks might not match the high bar set by “Down.” However, “Talk to Me” quickly eased that worry with its intriguing saxophone sounds, setting a promising tone for the album that it ultimately could not entirely maintain. Rather than focusing on lyrical depth, the album places its emphasis on creating a mood and incorporating unique sounds into each song. For example, “I Know Why” features a distinctive waterdrop effect. However, some tracks take a while to find their groove, and by the time they do, they’re nearly over. “Good” is a prime example, leaving you wanting more just as it hits its stride. The vocals often serve as another instrument, blending seamlessly with the music, making it clear that the focus is more on the atmosphere than the lyrics themselves. Occasionally, though, the lyrics and music feel out of sync, as if they were crafted separately without fully meshing. This can range from mildly annoying to quite distracting, possibly due to a mixing issue. The album maintains a laid-back yet engaging mood with a slightly dark edge. Marian Hill clearly aims to entertain, guiding listeners through various musical ideas. The experience somewhat dampened by weak vocal performance. Overall, “Act One” opens strong, falters somewhat in the middle, but manages to close on a high note. Highlights include “Down,” “Take Your Time,” “I Want You,” and “Mistaken.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rage Against The Machine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/29/Rage-Against-The-Machine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rage Against The Machine" /><published>2024-07-29T21:37:56+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-29T21:37:56+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/29/Rage-Against-The-Machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/music/2024/07/29/Rage-Against-The-Machine.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="rage-against-the-machine">Rage Against the Machine</h1>
<h2 id="album-rage-against-the-machine"><em>Album: Rage Against The Machine</em></h2>

<p>I’m not a fan of eponymous album names. Having to write “Rage Against the Machine” twice in a row—and needing to clarify that it wasn’t a mistake with the “Album:” prefix—only adds to my dislike. The fact that they technically have <em>two</em> eponymous albums doesn’t change my opinion. I’ll always be a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v9y51akm3N4">hater</a> at heart. But this might not be such a big issue for this album because Rage Against the Machine is a justifiably angry album.</p>

<p>Rage Against The Machine’s <em>Rage Against the Machine</em> <strong>should</strong> be an extremely contemporary album that points a finger at the issues the band identified at the time. However, as time has shown repeatedly, we’re all stuck on this hellride, and some of us are actively trying to get off. As a result, the album isn’t just contemporary to 1992; it’s relevant today as well.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>“Landlords and power whores, on my people, they took turns. Dispute the suits, I ignite and then watch ‘em burn.”</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>These lyrics feel as relevant today as they did back then—at least, I assume so, since I wasn’t born when the album came out. ~<em>Hi Bert, feel old?</em>~</p>

<p>Even <em>Killing In The Name</em> is as pertinent as ever, especially in light of <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/07/24/us/sean-grayson-illinois-police-officer-shooting-sonya-massey/index.html?iid=cnn_buildContentRecirc_end_recirc">yet another black person being murdered by the police for merely existing</a>.</p>

<p>The album is filled with lyrics that hit as hard today as they did back then. The music itself also hits just as hard, with riffs that get stuck in your head and what I assume is very experimental sounds. Proving that good music stays good.</p>

<h2 id="liked">Liked</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Unique soundscape, with lots of electric guitar played by someone who is an absolute master of their craft. I genuinely didn’t know someone could be that skilled at an instrument.</li>
  <li>They obviously had fun writing the music, and you can hear that in every aspect.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="disliked">Disliked</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Some songs don’t carve out their own unique musical identities and can blend together.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>I don’t like giving scores, so I won’t.
A great album that, unfortunately, remains as relevant today as it was back then.<br />
This album should be mandatory listening in 2024.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rage Against the Machine Album: Rage Against The Machine]]></summary></entry></feed>