<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Funny on Protobear.dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/funny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funny on Protobear.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Marnick De Grave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 20:00:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/funny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>r/MMORPG’s Greatest Hits (and Misses)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-best-of-r-mmorpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-best-of-r-mmorpg/</guid>
      <description>A (hopefully funny) look at the hatemail, toxicity, and memorable ‘personalities’ we’ve had the pleasure of moderating… so far.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past decade, we’ve compiled a vault of the most &rsquo;legendary&rsquo; commentary r/MMORPG has received. Some gems have been lost to time, but here’s what survived the purge. And just a heads up, not every comment was personally aimed at me; some were crowd-sourced by fellow mods who graciously shared their own &lsquo;fan mail&rsquo; and funny comments they came across.</p>
<p>But I think this poster said it best.</p>
<p>⚠️Trigger Warning
I&rsquo;m not one to quickly write a trigger warning, but there&rsquo;s a lot of racism, homophobia, misogyny and calls for death and suicide to be found in here. Like a LOT.</p>
<p>Ah, my first hatemail! Like a rite of passage, this was the one that officially welcomed me into the glamorous world of internet moderation. Nothing says &lsquo;you&rsquo;re doing great&rsquo; like a well-constructed accusation of a &lsquo;personal vendetta&rsquo; and an &rsquo;emotionally unstable character.&rsquo; It’s almost poetic, really. They didn&rsquo;t care &lsquo;in the slightest,&rsquo; yet here we are, two paragraphs deep.</p>
<p>Rope must have been on sale in the unhinged section, because here we have two people independently deciding that’s the best way to make their point.</p>
<p>Nothing says &lsquo;I’m a well-adjusted human being&rsquo; like rebranding your revolting preferences with a new label. Truly, these are the shining gems of r/MMORPG.</p>
<p>Nothing says teamwork like moderators questioning each other’s taste… and basic survival skills.</p>
<p>The dedication to calling others &lsquo;faggot&rsquo; or &lsquo;gay&rsquo; here is… impressive? Maybe if they put this much effort into learning game mechanics, they’d finally be able to complete an LFR difficulty raid.</p>
<p>I truly hope you’ve found what you’re looking for. May your search be as boundless as your dedication to… custom character adjustments.</p>
<p>Mod chat: where professionalism goes to die, and banter reigns supreme.</p>
<p>Some rants are so gloriously unhinged that it actually pains us a little to remove them.</p>
<p>Sometimes ya&rsquo;ll are just plain weird</p>
<p>If you’re going to throw insults, just know: our mods have comebacks locked and loaded.</p>
<p>After all the rants, the roasts, and the ridiculousness, it’s nice to remember that there’s a little good in every community. We’re lucky to have moments like these.</p>
<p>The tool we use to moderate Reddit rewards us with this little picture of a cat when the report queue is finally empty. It’s like our prize for surviving the chaos.</p>
<p>So here it is, as a reward. Thanks for enduring it all with us!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to coffee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ode-to-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 10:31:31 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ode-to-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee, thou art my tempestuous companion, both invigorating and soothing. When my mornings are heavy with languor, you change my frame of mind. Your warmth runs through me, awakening my senses and shaking me from my comatose state, with your rich, redolent floral aroma and your lustrous dark color. It feels as though I could reach out and touch velvet itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is comfort in the ritual of your preparation, the whirring of the grinder, the bubbling brew, and the rising perfume that fills my small kitchen while the day&amp;rsquo;s first light catches on the steam that rises from the cup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, thou art my tempestuous companion, both invigorating and soothing. When my mornings are heavy with languor, you change my frame of mind. Your warmth runs through me, awakening my senses and shaking me from my comatose state, with your rich, redolent floral aroma and your lustrous dark color. It feels as though I could reach out and touch velvet itself.</p>
<p>There is comfort in the ritual of your preparation, the whirring of the grinder, the bubbling brew, and the rising perfume that fills my small kitchen while the day&rsquo;s first light catches on the steam that rises from the cup.</p>
<p>For a moment while waiting, as I stretch and yawn, feeling the world drift by, I see my deep, tangled thoughts unravel. For just a moment, the world outside the kitchen ceases to exist, and there is only you and I.</p>
<p>You are both the comforting embrace that cradles me and the spark that ignites me; a codependent yet undeniably beautiful bond. Here&rsquo;s to you, coffee, the magic that brings the mundane to life, one glorious cup at a time.</p>
<p>So, to whom it may concern: Get the coffee machine fixed, or I will start invoicing my daily trips to Madmum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
