<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Games on Protobear.dev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games on Protobear.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Marnick De Grave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:02:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I didn&#39;t like Corepunk that much.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-didnt-like-corepunk-that-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:02:47 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-didnt-like-corepunk-that-much/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the summer, I finally purchased Corepunk, a game I had eagerly anticipated for years. Its top-down viewpoint, MOBA-inspired combat, and mixed progression systems promised a refreshing departure from the usual MMORPG formula. The aesthetic was striking, and the idea of a world that wouldn’t hold my hand through exploration intrigued me. After hosting an AMA for the game, the team even sent me a PR package, complete with my now-favorite socks and pen, which only added to my excitement. But as the saying goes, “The higher the climb, the harder the fall.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the summer, I finally purchased Corepunk, a game I had eagerly anticipated for years. Its top-down viewpoint, MOBA-inspired combat, and mixed progression systems promised a refreshing departure from the usual MMORPG formula. The aesthetic was striking, and the idea of a world that wouldn’t hold my hand through exploration intrigued me. After hosting an AMA for the game, the team even sent me a PR package, complete with my now-favorite socks and pen, which only added to my excitement. But as the saying goes, “The higher the climb, the harder the fall.”</p>
<p>When I first attempted to play Corepunk in the summer, I encountered a bug that prevented me from accepting the opening quest. Frustrating, but I chalked it up to the beta phase and resolved to try again after its soft launch in November. Unfortunately, my excitement soon turned into disappointment. After just 60 or so minutes of gameplay, I found myself logging out, disillusioned and frustrated.</p>
<p>Some of my frustrations are fixable, while others stem from what I see as core design flaws. My initial excitement about the game’s hands-off approach to navigation quickly morphed into my biggest annoyance: Corepunk doesn’t just fail to guide players; it actively undermines exploration with its lack of support.</p>
<p>I’ve broken down my core issues (pun intended) into three punkts (You see, the joke here is that punkt in German means point, I know, jokes are better when explained): Navigation, Questing, and Combat.</p>
<p>Navigation</p>
<p>One of the things I initially appreciated was the absence of big, flashing markers showing me where to go. I thought, “Finally, a game that trusts players to explore!” But Corepunk doesn’t complement this design choice with the tools needed to make exploration rewarding. Here are some key issues:</p>
<p>No Navigation Signs</p>
<p>There are no clear indicators of where to go. Buildings may have signs, but many require you to hover over symbols to understand what they represent. This breaks immersion and slows progress. I&rsquo;m not asking for big arrows leading me to my destination, but maybe a road sign or two. Or the ability to ask a guard?</p>
<p>Perspective Challenges</p>
<p>The top-down view, while aesthetically pleasing, makes it nearly impossible to rely on landmarks for navigation. You can’t look into the distance, and while this limitation is intentional, the terrain isn’t unique enough to compensate. Games like Diablo and Path of Exile work around this by designing corridors that naturally guide the player. Diablo 4 even incorporates vistas to provide a sense of direction. Corepunk, by contrast, leaves players adrift.</p>
<p>Unclear Quest Objectives</p>
<p>For one quest, I had to locate an NPC in a specific building. I remembered seeing the building before, complete with its sign, so I confidently went there. But when I tried to enter through the door next to the neon sign, it was locked and mentioned lacking a key. After wasting time trying to “solve” this puzzle, I discovered there was no puzzle and the NPC was actually in a nearby courtyard. With no visual indicators to identify them like, god, I don&rsquo;t know, how about their name above their head? To make matters worse, players crowded the NPC, and their wandering made it even harder to find them. The quest text didn’t clarify any of this, leaving me frustrated. ESO actually does this really well, if you were to turn off the UI and purely rely on quest text it does a really good job explaining you where you need to go.</p>
<p>This lack of clarity is more than frustrating: it’s exhausting. Fixing this would likely require a significant rework of the world design. For future zones, developers could add clearer visual cues and improved quest text to help players but I fear for the already in-game zones its too late.</p>
<p>Questing</p>
<p>Corepunk’s quest design only exacerbates its navigation problems. Here are three quests that highlight the issues and made me question my sanity:</p>
<ol>
<li>The First Optional Quest</li>
</ol>
<p>Early on, I spoke to an NPC (who had no name above their head or other indicators to suggest they offered a quest) who tasked me with searching barrels for mana crystals “on the farms.” With no map indicators or clear textual guidance, I spent several minutes searching the nearest farm—only to find nothing. Were the barrels elsewhere? Was it bugged? Did I misunderstand? The game offered no clarity, but it was listed as 1 or 2 levels above mine so I figured it might be in a farm elsewhere in the zone. I kept looking though. The next quest mirrors this problem a little bit.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>The Grain Hunt</li>
</ol>
<p>The second quest seemed simple: gather three grain to make flour. Yet this task took an infuriating 10 whole minutes. The quest vaguely mentioned finding containers on a farm (which one? not specified. There&rsquo;s dozens around), but interactable objects were incredibly sparse. Worse, some of the grain I eventually found wasn’t even located on a farm but at a butcher’s shop! Whether this was poor design or a bug, it felt like the game was actively working against me. I don’t think I can overstate how frustrating this was. I double-checked every farm and field to ensure I hadn’t missed anything. This wasn’t a case of “lol didn’t read.” I’m not exaggerating when I say it took 10 minutes to complete this simple task. I like to believe I&rsquo;m not dumb[citation needed] but this really made me question my intelligence.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Shove Your F****** Bread Up Your F******* Arse.</li>
</ol>
<p>After crafting flour into bread (a process the game handles partially for you, missing an opportunity for tutorialization), I had to go speak to different npc&rsquo;s. While exploring the area beforehand allowed me to see them on the map, this quest revealed a significant UI issue: the quest log and the overlay provided conflicting information. One included the NPCs’ names; the other didn’t. To access basic information, I had to awkwardly rearrange map windows, a clunky and unnecessary hurdle. But why would the overlay contain MORE information than the journal? That&rsquo;s just weird to me. And it was at this point I realized, this isn&rsquo;t just a singular issue. This has been my problem the entire time. Even with the first quest which leads you somewhere with a gigantic arrow pointing at nobody, only to open your map and see you were supposed to go elsewhere. The game does not want you to know where to go.</p>
<p>Combat</p>
<p>While I had high hopes that combat would redeem Corepunk, but it fell short in this area as well. Early fights rely heavily on auto-attacking, offering minimal strategy or engagement. The slow pacing and limited toolkit made encounters feel more like a chore than a challenge. For a game marketed as MOBA-inspired, this was a disappointing experience. While I imagine combat improves as you unlock more skills, the introductory fights failed to leave a strong impression. First impressions matter, and Corepunk squandered its chance to hook me.</p>
<p>Adding to the frustration is the painfully slow recovery process after combat. Healing outside of battle is a grind, either you run back to town (which feels absurd) or burn through consumables (a tolerable but uninspired solution). Since surviving two encounters in a row is nearly impossible early on, the downtime between fights becomes a tedious slog, slamming the brakes on an already slow-paced game.</p>
<p>It Might Pull Through</p>
<p>Despite my frustrations, Corepunk isn’t without merit. The visuals are stunning, and the world-building shows potential. If the developers address these issues, the game could shine in the long run. The combat, too, might become more engaging as players unlock additional abilities. But as it stands, Corepunk fails to live up to its potential.</p>
<p>I’ll give the game another chance at full launch, but I’m no longer holding my breath. With some serious overhauls, Corepunk could still become the game I once dreamed of playing. For now, however, all I can do is hope that they manage to fix its most glaring issues and finds a playerbase so that they can establish themselves and maybe work towards a version of the game that appeals to more people. Until then it serves as a reminder that even the most promising concepts can falter in execution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It doesn&#39;t matter what an MMORPG is.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/it-doesnt-matter-what-an-mmorpg-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/it-doesnt-matter-what-an-mmorpg-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I tried to write an article attempting to define what an MMORPG is after reading &amp;ldquo;What it means to be an MMORPG&amp;rdquo; by Bree Royce, who argues that the definition of an MMORPG is fluid and ever-evolving, making it impossible to define it rigidly. In my original post, I tried to be humorous and wrote, “Trying to define it is a fool’s errand. Today, I am that fool.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week I tried to write an article attempting to define what an MMORPG is after reading &ldquo;What it means to be an MMORPG&rdquo; by Bree Royce, who argues that the definition of an MMORPG is fluid and ever-evolving, making it impossible to define it rigidly. In my original post, I tried to be humorous and wrote, “Trying to define it is a fool’s errand. Today, I am that fool.”</p>
<p>Reader, you have no idea how much those words ring true because I wasted the better part of a weekend trying to make the article work. I made 11 different definitions. When I reached attempt #9 I made a formula for something I called the &ldquo;Social Interaction Possibility Space&rdquo;. In short: it aggregates scores across multiple dimensions of interaction to quantify how social a game is. But in the end it was still subjective because you need to derive your numbers from subjective data. And bullshit in, bullshit out.</p>
<p>The closest I got to something I even remotely agreed with was my final attempt, where I framed it as an &ldquo;online collaborative storytelling medium in a shared world&rdquo;, a bit like TTRPGs.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The genre is characterized by collaborative storytelling, shared persistence, and social engagement, fostering meaningful relationships and shared experiences among players.&rdquo;</p>
<p>As an analogy it has its use, but as a definition it falls short. So I started on attempt #12 by reading &ldquo;Presenting multiple node label support and graph mutability features of the Neo4j Graph Data Science in the Star Wars universe&rdquo;. This kickstarted a two-hour-long side quest trying to take a different approach, then something clicked and I realized I was wrong, and it cannot be done.</p>
<p>After nearly 9 years of hearing people complain about MMORPGs, I thought I had some grasp on what an MMORPG is. I was going to prove just how smart I was. But I wasn&rsquo;t smart, I was arrogant. and because of my arrogance I pissed away a weekend to come to the conclusion that Bree was right and had already handed to me the right answer on a silver platter. That the definition of an MMORPG is dynamic and ever changing.</p>
<p>The question “What is an MMORPG?” is flawed to begin with because it assumes there’s a universal, objective framework for defining a genre that is inherently subjective and deeply influenced by personal experiences, expectations, and cultural context. Like other complex, debated definitions, this question often gets entangled in the values, biases, and agendas of those answering it, rather than revealing an absolute truth.</p>
<p>At the end of the day does it even matter what is and isn&rsquo;t an MMORPG? Does it make a difference if Destiny 2 is objectively an MMORPG? We’re all raiding, running dungeons, competing in PvP matches, and tackling world events. Does the smaller size of Destiny’s zones really disqualify it from being compared to Guild Wars 2, a game where you&rsquo;re raiding, running fractals, competing in structured PvP/WvWvW and participating in open-world events? The DNA is too intertwined to dismiss the game as anything other than an MMORPG to me.</p>
<p>In her article, Bree presented a hierarchical family tree-style graph illustrating the evolution of MMORPGs. While this approach effectively represents historical growth, I personally think for depicting genres I&rsquo;d prefer a system where games are represented as interconnected nodes, with varying degrees of importance. Each game draws inspiration from a diverse range of other games. And perhaps even indicating how much influence they took from a certain game with varying line width.</p>
<p>And all a genre is, is us drawing imaginary lines around collections of games, attempting to group them together in a way that often doesn’t make sense. For instance, what genre is Portal? It’s a game where you solve puzzles that test your spatial and logical reasoning, along with your reflexes, presented as a first-person shooter. Simply labeling it as a puzzle game wouldn’t accurately describe its essence, and calling it a first-person shooter wouldn’t be incorrect either but would feel wrong. So, all we’re doing is limiting how much a developer can change until we no longer recognize it as an MMORPG. So, all that they can do is add another connection and maybe shift that border a tiny bit in the hopes that the genre perhaps moves enough over time.</p>
<p>I saw a screenshot of a Tumblr post the other day by the user Prokopetz about Dungeons &amp; Dragons, which came to mind while making this post that helped me with some insight.</p>
<p>Imagine a person who only consumes Batman-related media. That is, they only watch movies and TV shows that have Batman in them, only read books that are novelisations of Batman media, only play licensed Batman video games, and so forth. This is not so absurd an idea; Batman-related media is sufficiently popular, varied and widespread that restricting one’s media consumption in this way is completely feasible. However, I trust we can agree that if you actually do this, you will be left with very strange ideas about what popular media looks like.</p>
<p>The next step in this analogy is undestanding that if the only tabletop RPG you’re acquainted with is Dungeons &amp; Dragons, you have the same grasp of the tabletop roleplaying hobby as our hypothetical Batman Guy has of popular media.</p>
<p>This is what many people in the MMORPG space have, and at first I felt tempted to call out World of Warcraft but people have this with any game. These games require so much time investment that most players rarely engage with more than one MMORPG at a time. I&rsquo;m willing to bet most people don&rsquo;t even play more than one game at a time, period.</p>
<p>If your preferred MMORPG is Guild Wars 2, and you decide to try World of Warcraft, you might find WoW to feel lifeless because there aren’t any instances of 50 players in a zerg engaging in dynamic events. And if your MMORPG of choice is EVE Online, then most themepark MMORPGs might not even register as a real MMORPG to you. Everything is framed by the game you played first or enjoyed the most.</p>
<p>This phenomenon isn&rsquo;t limited to MMORPGs, think of a concept like Cozy Games. There’s a reason why almost everyone creates farming sims because many people believe that’s what cozy games are. However, they’re all mistaken! In my heart, and objectively, the pinnacle of cozy games is Animal Crossing: Wild World for the Nintendo DS. This is an undeniably correct and unquestionable statement.</p>
<p>So, where does that leave me? After all the definitions, the formulae, and mental gymnastics on a level that would get me to the olympics, I’ve come to realize that the question “What is an MMORPG?” was never the right question to begin with. I’m not even certain if I want to categorize it as a genre anymore; it’s more of a concept similar to cozy games. The question assumes a rigid definition for something that thrives on flexibility, subjectivity, and personal experience.</p>
<p>The right question is one that each of us has to answer for ourselves: “What do you get out of MMORPGs?” For some, it’s about the thrill of raiding with friends. For others, it’s the joy of getting lost in an expansive world, or the satisfaction of mastering intricate systems. For me, it’s the relationships, the sense of shared experience and collaborative storytelling in this virtual world we all inhabit. That’s what keeps me coming back to this genre, no matter how much it changes.</p>
<p>MMORPGs aren’t a static genre. They’re a conversation. A long, sprawling, messy conversation between players and developers, between communities and cultures, between what came before and what’s coming next. Trying to nail down a single definition is like trying to define a conversation by picking out one sentence. It misses the point.</p>
<p>Maybe that’s the beauty of MMORPGs. They resist definition because they’re too big, too diverse, too dynamic to be neatly boxed in. And maybe that’s why we keep playing them, not because we agree on what they are, but because they mean something different to each of us.</p>
<p>Or maybe I&rsquo;m just trying to romanticize this so I feel less bad about having wasted so much time trying to give it a definition anyway.</p>
<p>PS If it doesn&rsquo;t have fishing, it&rsquo;s not an MMORPG.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Dragon Age: The Veilguard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploring-dragon-age-the-veilguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exploring-dragon-age-the-veilguard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve dabbled in Dragon Age before, but never quite made the full commitment. So I went into The Veilguard with cautious excitement. With only around thirteen hours logged so far, I’m just starting to get my bearings. Still, there’s already plenty to talk about, both the good and the things that make me scratch my head a little. From world design to character development and combat, here are my first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve dabbled in Dragon Age before, but never quite made the full commitment. So I went into The Veilguard with cautious excitement. With only around thirteen hours logged so far, I’m just starting to get my bearings. Still, there’s already plenty to talk about, both the good and the things that make me scratch my head a little. From world design to character development and combat, here are my first impressions.</p>
<p>The Characters Need a Little More Roughness</p>
<p>One of the first things that stood out in The Veilguard is the characters. They are certainly memorable, but they almost feel too polished. So far, I’ve met four of them: Bellara, Harding, Lucanis, and Neve. Each of them has a unique personality, but I don’t get the sense that they connect with each other in meaningful ways or push the protagonist, Rook, to grow. They’re good people: morally solid, likable, and they never seem to waver from that. While I appreciate their virtues, I’d like to see more complexity. Lucanis hints at some moral ambiguity, but even his dilemmas feel idealized, framed by concepts of honor and goodness.</p>
<p>What strikes me is how each character seems to exist in their own bubble. Sure, there are some casual quips, but that’s about it. It would be much more compelling if Harding struggled with accepting Lucanis’s demon possession or if Neve occasionally got frustrated with Bellara’s unrelenting positivity. Right now, the lack of meaningful interaction keeps them from feeling like real people with real relationships. Sometimes, it feels like they are caricatures, each with exaggerated traits that don’t lead to any real tension or growth. In a world where curiosity and clashing ideals should naturally create conflict, I’m hoping to see more dramatic collisions between personalities as the story unfolds.</p>
<p>A Half-Open World: Refreshing, but Restrained</p>
<p>The world of The Veilguard opts for a half-open structure. This is different from the endless expanses of Skyrim or the complex, layered maps of Baldur’s Gate 3. It&rsquo;s almost closer to a linear game when you&rsquo;re playing through the story. It’s a choice that has a big impact on pacing, allowing the story to flow more intentionally. Instead of being dragged off into hours of side quests, I find myself tackling shorter, focused activities like a quick puzzle or an optional fight before jumping back into the main story. This format keeps the sense of urgency intact while still leaving room to revisit each zone for side quests later, unlocking larger parts of the map and seeing more of it. It’s refreshing, especially compared to games that end up turning every minor distraction into an hours-long saga.</p>
<p>However, this structure has its downsides. The world, while beautiful, often feels more like a meticulously crafted set than a living, breathing space. Treviso in Antiva, for example, is absolutely stunning, whereas Minrathous’s Dock Town has a grittier, gloomier feel; both are visually distinct but lacking in real interactivity. NPCs don’t react if you bump into them, and many areas are locked without a clear reason. Sometimes it’s hard to tell whether story progression or a puzzle will open the way. I also never feel these places are far away from each other. They feel more like thematic swaps than truly distant locations. And even when there are themes at play I am an observer rather than an actor in the world, there isn&rsquo;t any meaningful way for me to intervene in any conflict outside of dedicated quests, and I am just walking around freely in Minrathous even though I should have a target on my back.</p>
<p>Combat and Gameplay: Striking a Balance</p>
<p>The combat hits a nice balance between action and strategy. I’m playing as a mage, which suits me perfectly as I’ve always loved magic in RPGs. The tactical elements keep things exciting without getting into the overwhelming detail of Baldur’s Gate 3 or the more straightforward approach of Skyrim. The fights that stand out the most are the ones that make me think harder, while the lighter battles let me enjoy the action more casually, making encounters feel distinct. If I had to compare it to another game, I’d say it’s a bit like The Witcher, though it requires less prep work for the bigger fights.</p>
<p>One improvement I’d love to see is the ability to save different builds. Right now, I’m aiming for a spellblade setup, but I also like the deathcaller’s control-oriented abilities. A feature that let me save and switch between builds and armor would make experimenting much more enjoyable.</p>
<p>The Story: Making Lore Accessible</p>
<p>The story pacing feels well-balanced so far, but as someone who isn’t deeply familiar with previous Dragon Age games, I find myself wanting the lore to be more accessible. The codex entries are helpful, but they can pull me out of the game when I need to read them in detail. A simple fix would be narrated codex entries that I could listen to while exploring. I’d also love something like Destiny 2’s books, a way to gather pieces of lore in order and collect those I want to dive into more deeply. Maybe vendors could even sell those missing pieces, adding an extra layer to exploration. Or, hear me out, give me a mobile app. Yes, I know mobile tie-in apps typically suck, but if I have to read, at least let me read when I want to read, not when I want to play a video game. Reading the wiki isn&rsquo;t the same.</p>
<p>Dialogue choices are impactful, and I’ve already experienced some touching moments. One of my favorites was encouraging Harding to see her magic as a gift instead of something to fear. It’s these smaller, intimate choices that feel the most meaningful, and I hope they happen more often. I know these moments take a lot of writing effort, but they are what make RPG storytelling so special: the sense of being genuinely invested in the growth of my companions.</p>
<p>Where It Stands So Far</p>
<p>Overall, Dragon Age: The Veilguard is a polished experience that feels modern while staying true to its RPG roots. The half-open world is a welcome change, allowing for a focused kind of gameplay that’s hard to find in today’s sprawling, distraction-heavy games. It feels like BioWare decided to refine what makes a game immersive rather than expanding endlessly just for the sake of scale.</p>
<p>The Veilguard strikes a good balance for newcomers and RPG veterans alike, though I expect some players may resist the changes just because they’re different. Even so, I’m excited to see how the characters evolve, and I’m hoping they can break free from their archetypes and start interacting in more real, messy ways. If BioWare can keep refining this mix of action, strategy, and character-driven choices, The Veilguard could easily become one of my favorite games of the year. I’m having a blast, and I still can’t quite believe EA published it. There are no microtransactions, it doesn&rsquo;t require the EA Play launcher, nor does it require an online connection to play a single-player game. All this and more in 2024.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woolfe: A Belgian Fairytale with a Dark Twist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/woolfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 16:06:23 +0000</pubDate><author>reply@protobear.dev (Marnick De Grave)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/woolfe/</guid>
      <description>Belgian-made games don’t often make waves, but Woolfe from developer Grin has the potential to change that. With a mix of dark fairytales and rich visuals, it offers a promising glimpse into what indie games can achieve.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>⚠️Disclaimer
This article was first published in the November 2013 issue of G Van Games magazine, authored by me. In wanting to republish my earlier work I&rsquo;ve taken the opportunity to refine it and get rid of the word count restrictions the print version had. Think of it as a remastered version rather than a straightforward translation.</p>
<p>While the core content remains unchanged, certain sections have been polished to enhance clarity and flow. Please note, however, that no new information or updates have been added since the article’s original release.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, I had the chance to visit Grin’s studio in Antwerp to preview their latest project, Woolfe. It was a typical gray day in the city, setting an unintentionally fitting mood for the dark fairytale world the team is creating. While my time with the game was limited, I left with a solid understanding of the atmosphere Grin is aiming to capture, and the challenges they face as a small studio trying to deliver something special.</p>
<p>First Impressions: Atmosphere Over Mechanics</p>
<p>The first thing that stands out about Woolfe is its visual style. The game leans heavily on a dark, fairytale-inspired aesthetic, with clear nods to the Little Red Riding Hood story. The tone is grim, yet maintains a certain charm, using familiar fairytale elements in a way that feels fresh without becoming cliché. For an indie game, the polish on the visuals is impressive, even at this stage.</p>
<p>However, it’s important to note that I didn’t get much time to dive into gameplay mechanics. The demo I played was an early build, and many of the systems, from combat to puzzle-solving, are still being refined. It wouldn’t be fair to judge the gameplay based on this short experience, as what I saw was likely far from the finished product. What was clear, though, is that the team is focusing on creating a cohesive world first, and worrying about perfecting mechanics later.</p>
<p>Behind the Scenes: The Reality of Indie Development</p>
<p>While the game’s visuals grabbed my attention, the visit was also a reminder of the realities of indie game development. Grin is a relatively small studio, founded in 2002, and most of their previous work was focused on smaller, browser-based projects. Woolfe represents their first big leap into a larger, more ambitious project. Naturally, this comes with challenges.</p>
<p>During the visit, the team openly discussed the balancing act required to make a game like Woolfe with limited resources. Funding through initiatives like the VAF Game Fund has been crucial to the project’s progress, but indie development is always a race against time and budget. It’s clear that the developers are passionate, but that alone isn’t always enough to guarantee success. Watching the team juggle creative ambitions with the practical constraints of a small studio was a reminder of how difficult it can be to get a game like Woolfe off the ground.</p>
<p>What Lies Ahead for Woolfe</p>
<p>As this was an early build, there’s still much about Woolfe that remains uncertain. The developers themselves admitted they’re still finding the right balance between narrative, gameplay, and style. What I did play showed promise, but also left a lot of open questions. It’s one thing to craft a compelling atmosphere, but integrating that with satisfying gameplay is a challenge that many indie games face.</p>
<p>The combat and platforming elements I briefly experienced felt serviceable, though I didn’t spend enough time with them to get a real sense of depth. It will be interesting to see how these systems evolve as the game moves closer to release.</p>
<p>A Measured Outlook</p>
<p>It’s easy to get swept up in the excitement of seeing a game in development, but Woolfe is still very much a work in progress. What Grin has shown so far is promising, particularly in terms of visual direction and atmosphere. That said, indie development is unpredictable, and many hurdles remain between the current build and a polished final product.</p>
<p>Grin’s ambitions are clear, and they’re aiming to make a real impact with this title. Whether Woolfe can rise above the challenges and deliver on its potential will depend on how well the team can balance the various elements they’re still refining.</p>
<p>The Takeaway?</p>
<p>There’s no denying Woolfe has potential. The world Grin is building is visually engaging, and the concept of a darker, reimagined fairytale has definite appeal. But, as with any indie game in its early stages, there are still a lot of unknowns. What Grin has right now is a promising foundation, but the real test will be whether they can turn that foundation into a cohesive and enjoyable game by the time it’s ready for release.</p>
<p>For now, Woolfe is a project worth keeping an eye on, but it’s best approached with cautious optimism.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
